[MUSIC]
(音乐)
Stanford University, >> Welcome to Stanford CS193P,
斯坦福大学,斯坦福CS193P > >欢迎光临
Developing Applications for iOS, winter of 2017,
iOS应用程序开发,2017年冬天,
This is Lecture number 7, and today we're going to talk
这是讲座7号,今天我们要谈的
a little bit more about Swift, And once we do that,
更迅速,一旦我们这样做,
we can introduce some technology that we need
我们可以介绍一些我们需要的技术
to do more sophisticated UIKit objects like,
做更复杂的UIKit对象,
scroll views can be our first examples of that today's web
滚动视图可以是我们第一次的例子,今天的网络
demo at the end where we show you how to use scroll view,
演示结束后,我们向您展示如何使用滚动视图,
First thing I wanna talk about in Swift is error handling, So
首先我想谈谈在斯威夫特是错误处理,
far, we have not called any methods that
到目前为止,我们还没有任何方法调用
can generate an error, or what we call throwing an error, And
可以生成一个错误,或者我们称之为抛出错误,然后呢
we can always tell these methods though really clearly
我们总是可以告诉这些方法虽然很清楚
in any API, Because when they're declared,
在任何API,因为当他们宣布,
they'll have the word throws after it, And
他们会把这个词后,
throws means that somewhere in the processing of this method,
将意味着在该方法的处理,
it's possible, but not guaranteed, that it will throw
这是有可能的,但不能保证,它将抛出
an error, So when it throws that error at us,
一个错误,所以当它抛出错误在我们,
we have to catch the error, And the way we catch it is,
我们必须抓住错误,我们抓住它的方式,
well, first of all, every time we call a method
嗯,首先,我们每次调用一个方法
that can throw an error, we have to use the word try, So
可以抛出一个错误,我们必须使用这个词
we have to try that method because it might fail,
我们有尝试这个方法,因为它可能会失败,
So that's why we use the word try, But
这就是为什么我们使用这个词,但是
if we wanna catch the error that comes back,
如果我们想赶上回来的错误,
we actually have to do that little try inside what's
我们要做那个小尝试里面是什么
called a do construct, So we have to say do{, and
称为构造,所以我们不得不说做{,
then some code that has some tries in it, And then} catch,
然后一些代码有一些尝试,然后},
then let error is going to allow us to grab the thrown
然后让错误会让我们抓住扔
error into a variable, in this case called error,
错误到一个变量,在这种情况下叫错误,
We could say, let any variable name we want,
我们可以说,让任何我们想要的变量名,
That's gonna be the variable that has the error in it,
这是会有错误的变量,
And then in that curly brace, we handle the error, And
然后在花括号,我们处理错误的,
then after we've handled it, our code continues, So
之后我们处理它,继续我们的代码,所以
we caught the error, we deal with it, we keep going,
我们发现错误,我们应对它,我们继续,
It did, if we want to, and if our function throws,
,如果我们想,如果我们的函数抛出,
we could re-throw the error by using the keyword throw there,
我们可以抛出收到的错误通过使用关键字扔在那里,
in our second, little curly brace space, Now this error
在我们的第二个,小空间花括号,现在这个错误
that gets thrown to you, it does have to be of a certain
扔到你,它确实有一定的
type, The type is called error, It's a protocol,
类型,被称为类型错误,这是一个协议,
which I'm gonna talk about later in this lecture, but
稍后我要讲这节课,但是
it's a pretty simple little type,
这是一个非常简单的类型,
And in UIKit, when UIKit methods throw an error,
在UIKit,当UIKit方法抛出一个错误,
they throw an error of this type NSError, So
他们这种类型的抛出一个错误NSError,所以
you can go take a look in the documentation for NSError and
你可以去看一看NSError和文档
see what an NSError is, It has an error code, it has an error
看到一个NSError是什么,它有一个错误代码,它有一个错误
domain, like where the error occurred, And it,
域,如发生错误的位置,和,
even has some things like a description of what happened,
甚至有一些类似的描述发生了什么,
why it failed, things like that,
为什么它失败了,,
Now, sometimes we call a function that throws,
现在,有时我们调用一个函数抛出,
and we know for sure it's not going to fail, This is
我们确定它不会失败,这是
rare that we know this, but if we're certain about it,
罕见的,我们知道这一点,但如果我们确定,
we can use another version of try, which is try! And just
我们可以使用另一个版本的试试,试试!
like exclamation point means to force it in an optional,
像感叹号意味着迫使它在一个可选的,
exclamation point here means to force it essentially,
感叹号意味着迫使它从本质上讲,
And if we call context,save() right here,
如果我们调用上下文,保存(),
whatever that function is, if we call it and it throws,
不管这个函数是什么,如果我们叫它抛出,
our app will crash, okay, That's what the try!
我们的应用程序会崩溃,好吧,这就是试试!
means, It means try, I know this is not going to throw,
意味着,这意味着尝试,我知道这是不会扔,
If it does, crash my app, There's yet
如果是这样,撞击我的应用程序,然而
another try though, which is try?, Try?
另一个试试,试试?
means try to call this method that throws, and
意味着试图调用这个方法抛出,
if it does throw, just give me back nil,
如果它抛出,就给我回零,
Well, for
嗯,对
that to work of course, the variable that we're
当然,这工作我们的变量
assigning the result of this method, I called this one,
分配的结果,这种方法,我叫这个,
errorProneFunctionThatReturns- AnInt, Whatever that returns,
errorProneFunctionThatReturns AnInt,不管返回,
it's now gonna return an optional version of that,
现在要返回一个可选的版本,
So error prone function that returns an int,
所以容易出错的函数,它返回一个int,
returns an int obviously, But x,
返回一个int很明显,但x,
this let x =, that x is gonna be an optional int for
这让x = x是一个可选的整型
obvious reasons because if error prone function return
显而易见的原因,因为如果出错函数返回
an int throws, it has to throw nil back at us, okay? So
int抛出,它必须把零回到美国,好吗?
that's what try? is, Try? is give it a try, if it fails,
这就是试试吗?
just give me back nil, If I do this try, I don't get to
给我回零,如果我这样做,我不去
look at the error, I don't know what it is,
看这个错误,我不知道那是什么,
I'm ignoring the error here, I know there was an error, but
我忽略这个错误,我知道有一个错误,但是
that's all I know in the try? case, So it's a very simple
这就是我知道的尝试吗?
error mechanism that works quite well,
错误的工作机制很好,
In Swift they really learned the lessons of some other
在斯威夫特他们真的了解了一些其他的课程
languages that have more overwrought, over complicated
语言有更多的工作过度,太过复杂了
throwing of errors that are throwing up call stacks and
把错误的调用堆栈和呕吐
all these things, Swift is very straight forward,
所有这些事情,斯威夫特是非常直接的,
sees the entirety of the error processing, all right?
看到整个错误处理,好吗?
Now, another completely different topic, extensions,
现在,另一个完全不同的话题,扩展,
So, an extension allows you to add a method or a var,
所以,扩展允许您添加一个方法或者一个var,
even, to another class or structure enum, that you may
甚至,到另一个类或结构枚举,你可能
not even have the code to, okay, it's called extension
没有代码,它叫做扩展
because it extends that class, So, here's a concrete example,
因为它扩展类,所以,这是一个具体的例子,
I hope you understand why we might use an extension,
我希望你理解为什么我们可能使用一个扩展,
Remember when we did our app last time and
还记得我们上次我们的程序
we went to our Storyboard and we wrapped the detail of
我们去了我们的故事板,我们包装的细节
the split view in a navigation controller and
分割在导航控制器和视图
it broke our code, Right, it broke our code and
它打破了我们的代码,它打破了我们的代码
prepare for segue because that code was looking for
准备segue因为代码是寻找
a Face View controller and it found a navigation controller
一张脸视图控制器,它找到了一个导航控制器
instead, And the way we fix that is we just look to see if
相反,我们解决这个问题的方式是我们看看,看看
it was navigation controller first, And if it was, we look
这是导航控制器首先,如果是,我们看
at the visible view controller of the navigation controller,
可见视图控制器的导航控制器,
now we have our Face View controller back again, Now,
现在我们面临视图控制器回来,现在,
we could put that code into an extension of UIViewController
我们可以把这段代码到ui的延伸
by creating a new var, you can see it right here
通过创建一个新的变量,你可以看到它在这里
called contentViewController, we can call the new var
叫contentViewController,我们可以称之为新var
anything we want, I like contentViewController cuz
任何我们想要的,我喜欢contentViewController因为
if it's a navigation controller, it's the content,
如果它是一个导航控制器,它的内容,
If it's not a navigation controller, it's just self,
如果它不是一个导航控制器,它只是自我,
It's the view controller itself,
视图控制器本身,
It's its own content, And so I can add this, so
这是自己的内容,所以我可以添加这个,所以
I'm adding this var actually to UIViewController, So now
我添加这实际上var ui,因此现在
UIViewController understands this var, it has this new var,
理解这个var ui,这个新的var,
Now I didn't subclass UIViewController to do it,
现在我没有子类ui,
I just extended UIViewController, So
我只是扩展ui
you UIViewController and all subclasses of UIViewController
你和所有ui界面控制器的子类
will now have this var, And it makes that code that we had in
现在将有一个var,它使代码,我们有在吗
prepare, which looks something like this,
看起来像这样的准备,
the green part is the same in both places,
绿色部分是一样的在这两个地方,
It changes that code with all that to
代码和所有它改变
just this simple line of code, The segue's destination,
只是这个简单的代码行,segue的目的地,
contentViewController as my MVC, I think that slide says
contentViewController作为我的MVC,我认为幻灯片说
destinationViewController- that should be
destinationViewController——这应该是
segue,destination,contentView- Controller there, So,
segue,目的地,contentView -控制器,因此,
it just cleans up our code and prepare for segue, But
它只是清理我们的代码和准备segue,但是
the extension that we have UIViewControllers,
扩展uiviewcontroller我们,
purely a UIViewController thing,
一个单纯的ui的事情,
It has nothing to do with our emotions view controller,
它与我们的情感视图控制器,
anything like that, We purely extended UIViewController to
类似的,我们纯粹的扩展ui
have new functionality, Now, extensions inside their code,
现在有新功能,扩展他们的代码内部,
they can refer to self, And when they refer to self,
他们可以引用自我,当他们把自我,
they mean the class they're in, And so in this case,
他们的意思是类,所以在这种情况下,
the self means the UIViewController that
自我的ui
is executing this var which makes sense,
执行这个var是有意义的,
right? There's some restrictions though with these
对吧?
extensions, So extensions are not a substitute for
扩展,扩展是不能代替
everything object oriented like subclassing and
面向对象的子类化和一切
things like that, One thing is that you can't re-implement
类似这样的事情,有一件事是你不能重新实现
something that already is in there, So, you can't override
东西已经在那里,所以,你不能覆盖
or subclass with extensions, You can only add new things
或子类扩展,您只能添加新的东西
that aren't there, And in fact, if UIViewController were
没有,事实上,如果ui
to have implemented this var contentViewController,
实现这个var contentViewController,
its version would win- the extension with not win,
它的版本会赢——扩展与不赢,
In fact, it might even get an error when you try to add
事实上,它甚至可能会得到一个错误当你试图添加
an extension to something already there,
扩展已有的东西,
So its not our replacing or overriding or
所以它不是我们取代或覆盖
anything like that, it's for adding new things, And a huge
类似的东西,它是用于添加新事物,和一个巨大的
restriction to extensions is they cannot have any storage,
他们不能有任何存储限制扩展,
The only vars an extension can have have to be computed vars,
唯一var扩展可以计算var,
They can't have any stored vars, okay,
他们不能有任何存储var,好吧,
extensions have no storage, They are purely for
扩展没有存储,它们是纯粹的
adding code, all right, Now, this feature of extensions is
添加代码,好了,现在,这个功能的扩展
easily abused especially by beginners to Swift,
很容易滥用特别是初学者迅速、
They start saying, cool, I'll just add this code and
他们开始说,酷,我就添加此代码和
extension here, I'll add new code and
扩展在这里,我将添加新代码和
an extension there and I'll add it over there,
一个扩展那边,我会将它添加,
And you start getting this kind of messy situation where
和你开始这种混乱的情况
the extensions don't really make sense for
扩展并不真正意义
the class you added them to, So I'm gonna suggest that you
你加入他们的课,所以我要建议你
be kind of go slow and steady with the extensions,
是一种缓慢而稳定的扩展,
Don't use them too much, Now having said that, extensions
不要使用太多,现在已经说过,扩展
can be super powerful for architecting your code well,
代码可以是超级强大的架构,
Okay, especially when I start talking about protocols,
好,尤其是当我开始讨论协议,
They can be a fundamental aspect of building
他们可以建立一个基本的方面
like a functional programming approach to building your app,
像一个函数式编程方法来构建您的应用程序,
But I don't have time to teach all that to you, So
但是我没有时间教所有的给你,所以
you're only gonna know enough
你只会知道足够了
about extensions to get yourself in
关于扩展自己
a little bit of trouble, So be careful with extensions, okay?
有点麻烦,所以要小心与扩展,好吗?
Use them lightly, But in the future when you start
使用它们,但是在未来当你开始
a becoming serious iOS developer someday you're gonna
一个iOS开发者有一天你会变得严重
wanna learn how and you can use extensions to your
想学习,你可以使用扩展
advantage without abusing them, all right? Next topic,
优势没有虐待他们,好吗?
protocols, super, duper important topic here,
协议、超级欺骗者重要的话题,
How many people have encountered protocols in
有多少人遇到协议
other languages? Nobody, see? Well, one or two people,
其他语言吗?
So it surprises me a little bit, but, protocols,
所以我有点惊奇,但是,协议,
while very simple, are also incredibly powerful, So,
虽然非常简单,也非常强大,所以,
a protocol is a way to declare a type
协议是一种声明一个类型
that really just means these methods and vars with no
这只是意味着这些方法和增值没有
implementation generally, That's what a protocol is,
实现一般来说,这就是一个协议,
A protocol, as you'll see, is a type, But you're essentially
一个协议,您将看到,你本质上是一个类型,但
just defining a few methods, Or even some vars,
只定义一些方法,甚至一些增值,
that are part of this protocol, Then we're gonna use
这个协议的一部分,那么我们会使用
the protocol, as you'll see, to define our APIs better,
协议,您将看到,定义api更好,
It allows you to create an API that lets the callers pass
它允许您创建一个API,允许调用者通过
anything they want- any class, or struct, or enum even,
任何他们想要的——任何类或结构,或枚举,
they want to this API that you create, But it allows you,
他们想这个API创建的,但它允许您,
who's receiving it, to ensure that that class, or
谁是接收它,以确保类,还是
enum, or struct, implements certain methods or
枚举、结构、实现特定的方法或
vars that you need, So that's what this is all about,
var需要,这都是什么,
It's about API design, We want to build API so
关于API设计,我们希望构建API
we can express in our API exactly what we want and
我们在API可以表达我们所想要的
no more, Okay, just the methods and vars we need to do
没有更多的,只是我们需要做和增值的方法
whatever this function is going to do or whatever, and
无论这个函数是要做什么的,和
not extra stuff, So, a protocol is just a collection
没有额外的东西,所以,一个协议只是一个集合
of method and property declarations,
的方法和属性声明,
That's what a protocol is, But a protocol is a type, It's
这就是一个协议,但协议是一个类型,它是
a full fledged type, It serves any place you can use a type,
一个完整的类型,它任何地方您可以使用一个类型,
like a float, You can use a type that's a protocol,
像一个浮点数,您可以使用这种类型的一个协议,
Protocols are first-class types, Absolutely first-class
协议是一流的类型,绝对一流的
types, The implementation of the methods and vars under
类型,方法的实现和增值
protocol, since a protocol is just the declaration of them,
协议,自协议只是宣言,
where does the implementation happen? Well, mostly
实现发生在哪里?
it happens in classes and structs and enum that claim to
它发生在类和结构体和enum宣称
implement that protocol, or conform to that protocol,
实现这个协议,或遵守协议,
we say, So if I'm a struct, and I wanna say yes,
我们说,如果我是一个结构体,我想说是的,
I wanna conform to protocol x, then I have to implement
我想符合协议x,然后我必须执行
all the methods in vars that are in protocol x, right?
协议中的所有的var方法x,对吧?
Cuz protocol x is just a declaration of them,
因为x协议只是一个声明,
it's not an implementation, Now,
这不是一个实现,现在,
you can also do implementation on a protocol in an extension,
你还可以实现在一个扩展的一个协议,
but I'm going to put that on the shelf for second and
但是我要把第二和架子上
talk about that in a few more slides, But
讲到一些幻灯片,但是
primarily protocols, implementation happens in
发生在主要协议,实现
conforming or implementing classes,
符合或实现类,
structs and enums, Now, the three parts to a protocol,
结构体和枚举,现在,一个协议的三个部分,
One is the declaration of the protocol,
一个是协议的声明,
That's really simple, It looks just like declaring a class,
这是很简单的,它看起来就像声明一个类,
a struct or an enum, But there's no implementation,
一个结构或一个枚举,但没有实现,
okay, The second part is the class or structure or
第二部分是类或结构
enum that claims to conform to that protocol,
enum声称符合协议,
That claims that it implements that protocol, And
声称,它实现了协议,
then of course there's the actual code that that class,
当然有这个类的代码,
struct, or enum, that claims to implement the protocol,
结构体或枚举,声称执行协议,
actually does implement the protocol, So that's it,
确实执行协议,所以,
those are the three part of using a protocol,
这些都是使用协议的三个部分,
Both the declaration and then the implementation, Now,
声明和实现,现在,
I'm gonna talk about a feature with protocols,
我要讲一个特性与协议,
called optional methods, This is not optional,
可选的方法,这不是可选的,
like the optional type, This is different optional,
可选的类型,这是不同的可选,
It means that the methods in the protocol, are optional,
这意味着协议的方法,是可选的,
you don't have to implement them, and
你不必实现它们
you can still say that you implement this protocol,
你还能说你实现这个协议,
Now this is an Objective-C thing, This is not a really
现在这是一个objective - c的事情,这不是真的
a Swift thing, In swift when you have a protocol and
迅速的,在迅速,当你有一个协议
it has a bunch of methods in it, if you're struct or
它有很多方法,如果你是结构或
class and you wanna say you implemented that protocol,
类和你想说你那个协议实现的,
you have to implement all of them,
你必须实现所有这些,
all right, In Objective-C though that's not true,
在objective - c中,虽然这不是真的,
in Objective-C some of the methods might be optional and
在objective - c的一些方法可能是可选的,
in which case you can claim to implement the protocol and
在这种情况下,你可以要求执行协议
not implement those, So, if we have a protocol that has these
没有实现这些,所以,如果我们有一个协议,这些
optional things in it, it has to be marked objc,
可选的东西,它必须是objc,
So you put this little @objc before the word protocol, and
所以你把这个小@objc之前协议,这个词
that says this is an Objective-C protocol, And
说这是一个objective - c协议,
then inside the declaration you can put the word
你可以把这个词然后在声明
"optional" in front of any funcs or var that you want to
前面的“可选的”任何你想要的函数或变量
make optional, So this is going to be used for something
使可选,所以这将是用于什么
called delegation which I'm gonna talk about in a few
叫代表团在一些我要讲
slides which is an Objective-C thing that is brought forward,
幻灯片是一个objective - c提出了,
Because it's in UIKit so extensively it's brought
因为它在UIKit广泛了
forward into Swift using this @objc protocol, okay?
在迅速使用这个@objc协议,好吗?
But back to protocols in general, So let's take a look
但协议一般,让我们来看一看
at what a protocol looks like to declare,
协议是什么样子的申报,
So here's the declaration of a protocol called SomeProtocol,
这是协议称为SomeProtocol宣言,
And you can see it looks just like declaring a class,
你可以看到它看起来就像声明一个类,
a struct, or an enum, right,
结构体或枚举,
You got the keyword which is protocol instead of class,
你有协议的关键字,而不是类,
struct, or enum, Then you got the name,
结构体或枚举,然后你得到了这个名字,
Now after that though there's a colon, and other protocols,
现在,虽然有一个冒号后,和其他协议,
These protocols are called inherited protocols,
这些协议被称为继承协议,
Some protocol inherits these two protocols, And
一些协议继承这两个协议,
what it means is that anyone who wants to say yeah,
这意味着,任何人想说,
I implement some protocol,
我实现一些协议,
they have to implement those too,
他们必须实现这些,
Okay, they're doing all three of these protocols,
好的,他们做所有这三个协议,
Some protocol, and its two inherited protocols,
一些协议,它的两个继承协议,
So protocols essentially have multiple inheritance, How many
所以协议本质上有多重继承,有多少
people know what multiple inheritance is in object
人知道什么是多重继承的对象
oriented? So only a few of you, So multiple inheritance
面向?
just means like you could have two super classes, or
就意味着你可以有两个父类,或
three super classes, Some languages support that,
三个超类,有些语言支持,
Swift does not, But Swift does support multiple
斯威夫特没有,但迅速并支持多个
protocols that you can inherit from, okay?
协议,你可以继承?
Now, the protocol inside, you can have properties and
协议里面,现在你可以有属性和
you can have funcs, And if you have a var, a property,
你可以有函数,如果你有一个var,一个属性,
you have to say whether it's a get set property or
你不得不说这是一个是否得到或设置属性
there's just get only and you do that in a curly brace get
只有只有你用花括号
set, Curly brace get, So you have to put that curly
集,花括号,所以你必须把卷曲的
brace something in there that says whether you're gonna be
撑在那里,你是否会说
a get set var or whether you're just a get-only var,
一组得到var还是你只是一个只有get var,
Any function that the protocol expects would mutate the thing
任何函数,该协议预计会发生变异
implementing it, like if a struct were implementing it,
实现它,就像如果一个结构体实现它,
you have to mark it mutating, Now if a class were to
你必须马克现在变异,如果一个类
implement this protocol, it wouldn't matter,
实现这个协议,它不重要,
classes don't have to mark themselves mutating,
类不需要马克自己变异,
And in fact it's even possible to say,
事实上,它甚至可能说,
I want this protocol only to be implemented by classes,
我只希望这个协议实现的类,
And you do that by putting the word class right after
和你用这个词之后
the colon, See the yellow class right there SomeProtocol
冒号,看到黄色类SomeProtocol
: class- that means this SomeProtocol can only be
:类——这意味着这个SomeProtocol只能
implemented by reference types, And
实现的引用类型
in that case you don't have to put any mutatin's in there,
在这种情况下你不需要放任何mutatin,
But if you are gonna allow your protocol to
但如果你要让你的协议
be implemented by an enum, or especially by a struct,
实现由一个枚举,或者特别结构,
obviously you're gonna have to put mutating in there,
很明显你需要把变异,
You can also specify in a protocol initializers,
您还可以指定在一个协议的初始化,
You're basically saying,
你基本上说,
anyone who wants to implement this SomeProtocol has to be be
任何人想要实现这个SomeProtocol必须是
able to be initialized with these arguments, all right?
能够与这些参数初始化,对吧?
If you do that, by the way, and you're a class,
顺便说一下,如果你这样做,你是一个类,
okay, then you have to mark the initializer required, I'll
好吧,那么你必须马克所需的初始化,我会
show you that in a second, All right, so how does a class or
告诉你,,好吧,那么一个类或
a struct or an enum say yes, I implement SomeProtocol?
一个结构或一个枚举说,是的,我实现SomeProtocol吗?
It does it this way, A class, right after its superclass,
这样,一个类,其超类之后,
just puts a comma and the protocols'll do this,
只是把一个逗号和协议将会这样做,
And you can implement any number of protocols there,
你可以实现任意数量的协议,
So this class called SomeClass has a SuperClass,
这类被称为SomeClass有一个超类,
it's called SuperClass of some class, and it also implements
它叫做一些类的超类,它还实现了
two protocols, SomeProtocol and AnotherProtocol,
两个协议,SomeProtocol AnotherProtocol,
Now inside of SomeClass' implementations it must
它必须现在SomeClass的内部实现
implement all the methods and vars in those two protocols
实现和增值的所有方法在这两个协议
unless it's an Objective-C protocol and they're marked
除非是一个objective - c协议和标记
optional, Okay, the methods in there are marked optional,
可选的,在有可选的方法,
That's the only exception to that, All right, Structs or
这是唯一的例外,结构或
enums, Exactly the same, it's just they have no superclass,
枚举,一模一样的,只是他们没有父类,
So here's an enum saying, that it implements those two
这是enum说,它实现了这两个
protocols, okay? And here is a struct saying that it
协议,好吗?
implements those two protocols, Now,
实现这两个协议,现在,
you can have any number of protocols implemented, And
你可以拥有任意数量的协议实现
as I said, inits have to be required, The reason that
就像我说的,init必须需要的原因
these inits have to be required here is that,
初始化必须要求是,
what if a subclass, subclass is SomeClass right there, and
如果一个子类,子类SomeClass,和
it does all the initial exation games such as,
它所有的初始exation游戏,比如,
this is no longer a good intializer,
这不再是一个好的intializer,
Because maybe this was required,
因为也许这是必需的,
You need an initializer, you need an override, so
你需要一个初始化程序,您需要一个覆盖,所以
now you have your own new designated initializer,
现在你有了自己的新的指定初始化,
et cetera, Well, that would be bad, because that would mean
等等,这将是糟糕的,因为这意味着
the subclass of SomeClass would no longer conform to
SomeClass不再符合的子类
that protocol, and that is not allowed,
协议,是不允许的,
If a class conforms to a protocol, like SomeProtocol,
如果一个类符合协议,像SomeProtocol,
all of its subclasses have to continue to do that, And
所有的子类必须继续这样做,和
they'll inherit that from the superclass except for init,
他们会从超类继承,除了初始化,
are the one thing that can be uninherited by the rules of
的一件事是可以uninherited的规则吗
init, Okay? One thing that's very interesting is that you
初始化?
are allowed to add protocol conformance to a struct,
允许添加协议一致性结构,
a class, or an enum using an extension, As long as you can
一个类,或者使用一个扩展枚举,只要你能
do it without any storage, You can do it in the extension,
这样做没有任何存储,你可以扩展,
You just say, extension Something, where Something is
你只是说,扩展的东西,东西在哪里
the class, struct or enum, colon, SomeProtocol,
类、结构或枚举、结肠癌、SomeProtocol,
And that saying, I'm creating extension to that class,
说,我创建扩展类,
struct or enum that implements this protocol,
结构体或枚举实现这个协议,
And then inside that extension,
然后在扩展,
you have to implement all the methods of the protocol, Okay,
你必须实现所有协议的方法,好的,
understand what I'm saying there? Let's
明白我的意思吗?
talk about protocols being types, What do I mean when I
讨论协议类型,什么我的意思是当我
say a protocol is a type? So, I got an example here,
说协议是一个类型?
I've got a protocol called Moveable and
我有一个叫做移动和协议
it just has one function in it, a mutating function called
它有一个函数,一个变异函数调用
move to point, Now, I have two data structures here,
点,现在,在这里,我有两个数据结构
One is a class called Car, and it's Moveable,
一个是一个类称为汽车,它是可移动的,
Okay, the Car is Moveable, but the Car also has other methods
好的,车是可移动的,但是汽车也有其他的方法
like changeOil, You change the oil of the car, And
像changeOil,你改变汽车的油,和
similarly I have this struct called Shape,
同样我有这种结构称为形状,
It also implements Moveabl, Look, see, mutating func
它还实现了Moveabl,看,看,变异函数
move to point, It actually implements that, But it also
点,它实际上实现了,但它也
has a function called draw, Because it is a shape and
有一个函数叫做画,因为它是一个形状和
it can be drawn on screen, All right, so all
它可以在屏幕上,所以
two of these classes implement this protocol move to,
两个类实现此协议转向,
Do you see that? So do you see that they're all moveable?
你看到了吗?
Okay, a car is moveable, A shape is moveable,
好的,汽车是可移动的,形状是可移动的,
That's how we would describe those, So I created two little
我们将描述这些,所以我创建了两个小
vars down here, A Prius, which is of car of course,
var,普锐斯,这是汽车当然,
it equals a new car, And then I created a square,
它等于一辆新车,我创建了一个广场,
which is a shape, of course, So I've got a Prius and
这是一个形状,当然,所以我有普锐斯和吗
a square here, Let's see what we can do with the Prius and
一个广场,让我们看看我们能做什么和普锐斯
the square, First, I can create a var whose type is
广场,首先,我可以创建一个变量的类型
Moveable called thingToMove and I can assign it to Prius,
可移动的叫做thingToMove我可以将它分配给普锐斯
Because a Prius is moveable, So if I have a var that
因为普锐斯是可移动的,所以如果我有一个var
is of type moveable, of course a Prius can be put in there,
的类型是可移动的,当然普锐斯可以放在那里,
Everyone understand that? And I can even say, thingToMove,
大家都理解了吗?
move to this point, because thingToMove is a Moveable,
搬到这一点,因为thingToMove是一个可移动的,
So, if it's a Moveable, it has to implement move to point, So
所以,如果这是一个可移动的,它必须实现转向点,
I can say that, However, I cannot say, thingToMove,
但是,我可以说,我不能说,thingToMove,
change oil, This is the critical thing to understand,
改变石油,这是关键的理解,
okay? Even though I put a Prius in thingToMove,
好吧?
that var is not a Car, it's a Moveable,
var不是一辆车,它是一个可移动的,
And moveables don't know how to change the oil, Cars do,
和可移动的不知道如何改变石油,汽车,
But moveables don't, So what matters is the type when it
但可移动的,所以重要的是当它类型
comes to sending the messages, not what's actually in there,
来发送消息,而不是实际上是什么,
Everyone understand that? Now, of course, I could also say
大家都理解了吗?
thingToMove = square, That's perfectly legal as well, Okay,
thingToMove =广场,这是完全合法的,好的,
square is not even a class, it's a struct, Okay,
广场甚至不是一个类,它是一个结构体,好吧,
it's not a car, it's a shape, But they're both moveable so
它不是一辆车,它的形状,但它们都是可移动的
that var thingToMove which is of type Moveable can hold
var thingToMove这类型的可移动的可以
either of those things, In fact, I can even create
这些东西,事实上,我甚至可以创建
an array, thingsToMove, which is an array of Moveable and
一个数组,thingsToMove,这是一个可移动的和数组
then I can put a Prius and a square both in there,
然后我可以把普锐斯和一个正方形,
even though they're completely different classes,
尽管它们完全不同的类,
types of things,
类型的东西,
They can both go in there cuz they're both moveables,
他们可以进去,因为他们都是可移动的,
So, the type of thing in that array is Moveable,
所以,在这个数组的类型是可移动的,
What it actually is, doesn't matter, Okay,
它实际上是什么,没关系,好吧,
everyone cool with that? All right, I could also have
每个人都明白了吗?
a function that takes a Moveable as an argument,
一个函数,它需要一个可移动的作为参数,
like slide that takes a slider which is a Moveable, and
像幻灯片需要一个可移动的滑块,和
I can say, slider move to that position because the argument,
我可以说,滑块移动到那个位置,因为参数,
slider, is a Moveable so we can say move too, And
滑块,是一个可移动的所以我们可以说,和
I could say slide a Prius, slide a square,
我可以说幻灯片普锐斯,滑动一个正方形,
It works perfectly fine, By the way you can have arguments
效果非常好,你可以有参数
to functions that require multiple protocols,
需要多个协议的函数,
For example I could have a function, slip and
例如我可以有一个函数,滑
slide which has a parameter x which is both Moveable,
滑参数x是可移动的,
and another protocol, which I haven't showed here,
另一个协议,我这里还没有显示,
called Slippery, And that's what the ampersand means,
称为滑,该符号是什么意思,
It means both of these protocols, So
这意味着这两个协议
that inside slipAndSlide, I could send x Moveable things,
slipAndSlide里面,我可以发送x可移动的东西,
like move to, and I could also send it Slippery things,
喜欢去,我也可以把它滑的东西,
whatever those are, Note that I can't say slipAndSlide
不管这些,请注意,我不能说slipAndSlide
Prius, because Prius does not implement slippery, okay?
普锐斯,因为普锐斯没有实现滑,好吗?
Prius does not conform to the Slippery protocol so cannot
普锐斯不符合协议所以不能很滑
pass in there, Swift would not even let me call that,
迅速传递,甚至不让我叫,
Okay, everyone understand what I mean now by a protocol as
好了,大家都明白我的意思是现在通过一个协议
a type? It's just a type, and anything that conforms to that
一个类型?
type can be stored in something, or passed through
类型可以存储在一些东西,或通过
in something of that type, Now I'm gonna take a couple slides
在该类型的东西,现在我要花几幻灯片
here and talk about the advanced use of protocols, I'm
这里讨论的高级使用协议,我
not gonna ask you to do that in the nine or ten weeks we
不会让你做我们在九、十周
have here because it is kinda advanced use, But I think it's
这里,因为它是有点高级的使用,但我认为这是吗
important that you understand that this exists because all
重要的是你明白这,因为所有的存在
of Swift's standard library, arrays and dictionaries,
斯威夫特的标准库、数组和字典
all that stuff, is all implemented using protocols,
所有的东西,都是使用协议,实现
So, one thing that a protocol can do that I'm not gonna ask
协议可以做的一件事,我不会问
you to do, is that it can restrict the type
你做的,就是它可以限制类型
of a generic, Everyone knows what a generic is, right?
一般,每个人都知道什么是一个通用的,对吧?
An array of angle bracket t,
尖括号的数组,
It means the array can hold any type in there, But that t,
这意味着数组可以保存任何类型,但t,
that array of t could be restricted to things that
这一系列t可能限制的事情
implement a certain protocol, So here's an example,
实现一个特定的协议,这是一个例子,
which is range, When I showed you range, a few lectures ago,
范围,当我给你们看的,几年前的一个讲座,
I said it was sort of Range, Okay,
我说这是范围,好吧,
the reason it was only sort of Range was because
原因只有范围是因为
actually range bound or T bound is just a variable name
实际上范围约束或T绑定是一个变量名
basically for that type, colon comparable,
基本类型,结肠相比,
Okay, so a range can only be a range of things that implement
好的,所以一系列只能实现一系列的事情
the protocol Comparable, Luckily ints implement
协议相比,幸运的是整数实现
Comparable, Floats implement Comparable, Characters and
可比,浮点数实现可比性,人物和
strings implement Comparable, etc, So these things all
字符串实现可比性等,所以这些东西
implement Comparable so you can have a range of ints,
实现类似的所以你可以有一个范围的整数,
a range of floats, whatever, Now,
一系列的花车,无论如何,现在,
why does range want the thing in its range to be comparable?
为什么想要在其范围内的范围可比?
Well it's because it wants to make sure that its lower bound
这是因为它希望确保其下界
is always less than its upper bound,
总是小于其上界,
I think on the other slide, I said it was start index and
我想在另一张幻灯片,我说这是指数和开始
end index, Which is actually not range, the range struct,
结束指数不是范围、结构、范围
that's countable range, and those kind of things have
可数的范围,这些事情
that, You rarely use just a straight range,
你很少使用只是一个连续范围,
You're almost always using the countable range,
你几乎总是使用可数的范围,
or closed countable range, or one of those, But anyway, so
或关闭可数范围,或其中的一个,但无论如何,所以
that's why it wants the type that it can be generic for
这就是为什么它希望它可以通用的类型
to be Comparable, So
类似的,所以
being able to restrict this generic types by some protocol
能够限制这个泛型类型的协议
is really super powerful, Okay, because it allows you to
是非常强大的,因为它允许您
build much a more wide variety of generic data structures,
构建一个更广泛的通用的数据结构,
Because you can make it so
因为你可以让它如此
that they have to implement certain things to work,
他们必须实现某些事情,
All right, Now, also, you can use
现在,您可以使用
generics to declare protocols, So you can have protocols,
仿制药申报协议,所以你可以有协议,
where the methods in vars might be a generic type, So,
在var的方法可能是一个泛型类型,因此,
now you can have these protocols kind of meta,
现在你可以有这些协议元,
But you can have these protocols that can be
但是你可以拥有这些协议,可以
describing behavior that can work on generic types,
描述行为,可以工作在泛型类型
Or maybe work on generic types that implement certain
或者工作上实现特定的泛型类型
protocols, Now, this is probably hard for you to
协议,这可能是你很难
imagine where this could go, but it really can go,
想象这可能去的地方,但它真的可以,
Okay, so you're really opening up a lot of power here
好的,所以你真的开放大量的电力
by adding generics, And constraining these generics
通过添加泛型,以及这些泛型约束
using protocols, Again remember that you kind
再次使用协议,记住你
of get multiple inheritance with protocols, And I'm
有多重继承协议,我
going to show you an example here with CountableRange,
与CountableRange将向你们展示一个例子,
So CountableRange is the type of struct you get if you use
所以CountableRange结构得到如果你使用的类型
3,,<5, Remember I showed you that, Like if you're doing a 4
3、< 5,记住我给你,就像如果你做一个4
in and you want to come forward to 5 non inclusive,
在你想要上前5非包容,
use three dot dot five you get this countable range,
使用三点点五你得到这个可数范围,
Well, le's think what CountableRange is,
勒的认为CountableRange是什么,
CountableRange is a struct that implements a ton
CountableRange实现一吨是一个结构体
of protocols,
的协议,
Here's some of the interesting ones it implements,
这里有一些有趣的它实现,
IndexableBase which gives it start start index and end
IndexableBase使它开始开始指数和结束
index which I showed you on that slide kind of erroneously
指数,我给你们看,幻灯片上的错误
as Range, it also implements this method index
作为范围,它还实现了这个方法指数
after, So, a range can move forward cuz you can always
之后,一系列可以因为你总是可以前进
find the next index, And it also does subscripting,
寻找下一个指数,它也加下标,
so you can take a range and get subscript sub three, and
所以你可以设定一个范围,让下标子3和
it will get you the fourth one in there, Right,
它会让你第四个,对了,
so that protocol's called IndexableBase, Then there's
这协议被称为IndexableBase,还有
another protocol called Indexable, Which actually
另一个协议被称为可转位,实际上
inherits from IndexableBase which has index offsetBy,
继承自IndexableBase offsetBy指数,
So now you can move through the range more than just to
现在你可以穿过不仅仅范围
the next one, you can move farther ahead,
下一个,你可以移动更远的未来,
There's also BidirectionalIndexable,
还有BidirectionalIndexable,
Now you can go backwards, index before, okay, So
现在你可以倒退,索引之前,所以
these things like startIndex, index after, index offset,
这些事情像startIndex,指数后,指数抵消,
index before, these are just methods in these protocols,
索引之前,这些只是这些协议中的方法,
It also implements this very important protocol called
它还实现了这个非常重要的协议
Sequence, And the main method in Sequence is makeIterator,
序列,序列的主要方法是makeIterator,
Which gives back an object that can do the for in thing,
使一个对象,可以做的的事情,
So a Range, that's why Range works with for in,
所以一个范围,这就是为什么使用的范围,
because it implements the Sequence protocol, And
因为它实现了序列协议,
it also implements the Collection protocol,
它还实现了协议集合,
But Collection is primarily just an indexable sequence,
但是收集主要是只是一个可转位序列,
So it implements both those protocols- things that
所以它实现了这两个协议的事情
are collections implement both those protocols,
集合实现这两个协议,
So why does Apple go to all the trouble
为什么苹果去所有的麻烦
to take something simple like a CountableRange and
采取一些简单的像CountableRange
make it implement all of these ridiculous protocols?
使其实现这些荒谬的协议吗?
Well, here's why, Because Array also implements all
这是为什么,因为数组还实现了
those protocols and so there's Dictionary and Set and
这些协议有字典和设置
String,UTF16View, The thing that will let you see Unicode
字符串,UTF16View,会让你看到Unicode
characters in the string, All of these things do, So they're
字符的字符串,所有这些事情,所以他们
all sharing the same basic API description of their behavior,
所有共享相同的基本API的描述他们的行为,
Even though they're quite different,
即使他们是完全不同的,
An array is quite different from a range, A set
数组从一系列完全不同,是一个集
is different than an array, And certainly a, character,
数组是不同的,当然,性格,
UTF16View, is different than any of those things,
UTF16View,比任何这些东西是不同的,
They're dictionaries, So these are all different things,
他们的字典,所以这些都是不同的东西,
But they share the behavior of being indexable,
但他们分享的行为可转位,
being a sequence of things, being collections of things,
一系列的事情,被收藏的东西,
they share all that behavior,
他们分享所有的行为,
And so that's described with these protocols and wait,
这就是描述这些协议和等待,
there's more, Because of this thing I told you that
有更多的,因为这事我告诉过你
extensions can be used to add code to a protocol,
扩展可以用来添加代码协议,
okay, Now there's restriction there, of course, because both
好的,现在有限制,当然,因为两个
protocols and extensions can have no storage,
协议和扩展没有存储,
So if you extend a protocol and
所以如果你扩展协议
give it some actual implementation,
给它一些实际的实现,
by implementing some of the methods in the protocol,
通过实现协议的一些方法,
You can only use other methods in the protocol, Or
你只能使用其他方法的协议,或
methods you inherit from other protocols,
方法继承其他协议,
right? You can't use any storage,
对吧?
All you can do is call other methods and vars, But
你所能做的就是调用其他方法和增值,但是
you'd be surprised how much you can do when you do that,
你会很惊讶你能做多少,当你这样做,
And what that allows you to do,
这允许你去做,
in this case, if you consider Sequence, I told you that
在这种情况下,如果你考虑序列,我告诉你
Sequence mostly just makes you that makeIterator thing,
序列大部分只是让你makeIterator的事情,
So, you can for in through the string characters or
所以,你可以在通过字符或字符串
through the array or through the range or whatever, Well,
通过数组或范围之类的,嗯,
if you just implement that one method, Apple has provided
如果你只是实现这一方法,苹果提供了
an extension to the Sequence protocol, That implements two
序列的扩展协议,实现两个
dozen other methods that are based on being able to iterate
其他方法都是基于迭代
through, Like contains, is this thing contained in this
通过包含一样,这是包含在这
Sequence? Or joined by separator, which will take
序列?
each thing in the sequence, turn it into a string, and
序列中的每一件事,把它变成一个字符串,和
join it by whatever separator you say, like a comma, and
加入你说无论分离器,像一个逗号,
give you back a string, Okay? Or min and max,
返回一个字符串,好吗?
What's the minimum thing, or the maximum thing?
最小的事情,还是最大的?
Of course in that case,
当然在这种情况下,
the sequence would have to have what, comparable
序列会有什么可比性
items? You have to be able to compare them, If you're gonna
物品吗?
do min or max, Even those cool functions I told you,
做最小或最大,即使那些很酷的功能我告诉你,
filter and map, remember those? That took a closure and
过滤和地图,还记得这些吗?
you were able to map an array from one thing to another,
你可以地图从一件事到另一个数组,
You can do the same thing with a range, And
与范围,你可以做同样的事情
that code is not in Array, It's in this extension of
这些代码不是数组,它在这个扩展
Sequence, Okay, so now you're actually inheriting
序列,好了,现在你可以继承
true implementation, true functionality, And
真正的实现,真正的功能,
you're multiply inheriting it, okay? And
你将继承它,好吗?
you're doing it in a generic way so
你用它来做一个通用的方法
that the code works on arrays, string characters, etc,,
代码适用于数组,字符串字符,等等,,
equally, Okay, so hopefully, that's given you some feel for
同样,好的,希望给你一些感觉
like whoa, what you could do if you had these protocols?
哇,如果你有这些协议你可以做什么?
If you've designed your API using protocols,
如果你设计的API使用协议,
And then, you could add code like this using extensions,
然后,您可以使用扩展,添加下面这样的代码
You can hopefully see, and use generics especially, you could
希望你能看到,特别是使用泛型,你可以
see how you could reuse a lot of code, Now this approach, I
看看你可以重用代码,现在这种方法,我
actually mentioned it before, This approach of focusing on
其实之前提到的,这种方法的关注
the behavior of things rather than on the storage,
事物的行为而不是存储,
Is leading to a methodology called functional programming,
导致称为函数式编程的方法,
And again, I can't teach you that unfortunately, but
再一次,我不能教你,不幸的是,但是
I want you to know it exists, And maybe you can take
我想让你知道它的存在,也许你可以
a course here where you can learn about it,
当然在这里,你可以了解它,
If you go out to the outside world, self-teach
如果你出去外面的世界,self-teach
yourself if you have to, It's very powerful mechanism for
自己如果有,非常强大的机制
programming, And the protocols and
编程,和协议
generics play right into this, Because protocols and generics
泛型游戏,因为协议和泛型
are all about the behavior of things, not about their
都是关于事物的行为,而不是对他们吗
storage, Okay, all right, That's all I can unfortunately
存储、好了,好了,这就是我可以很不幸
have time to say about the functional programming and
有时间说函数式编程和吗
protocols, And now let's back way up off of
协议,现在我们回来的
advanced protocols and
先进的协议和
start talking about a couple of simple uses of protocols,
开始谈论一些简单的使用协议,
Here's a simple protocol that you could use right now in
这是一个简单的协议,现在您可以使用
your calculator, It's called CustomStringConvertible,
你的计算器,它叫做CustomStringConvertible,
And it only has one thing in the protocol which is a var,
它只有一件事是一个var的协议,
It's a get-only var called description, Looks familiar?
这是一个只有get var称为描述,看起来熟悉吗?
Which is a string, And if you implement this protocol,
这是一个字符串,如果你实现这个协议,
then when you print, if you do the backslash,
当你打印,如果你反斜杠,
parenthesis thing and put your thing inside, It will call
括号里面东西,把你的东西时,它将调用
this description to get the description of it, So right
这个描述的描述,所以正确的
now, if you said, print quote \ ( your CalculatorBrain,
现在,如果你说,印刷报价\(你的计算器大脑
in your view controller, ), it would probably print out some
在你的视图控制器,),它可能会打印一些
hexadecimal number and the word CalculatorBrain, which is
十六进制数和计算器大脑这个词
useless, But if you put colon CustomStringConvertible after
无用的,但如果你把结肠CustomStringConvertible之后
your struct CalculatorBrain, now, when you print it out,
你现在的struct计算器大脑,当你打印出来,
it'll print out the description, In other words,
它会打印出描述,换句话说,
the equation, right, because you implement description
方程,对吧,因为你实现描述
already, I intentionally chose the name description there
已经,我故意选择名称描述
so that you would implement CustomStringConvertible
这样你会实现CustomStringConvertible
automatically, But you have to also say that you implement
自动,但你必须也说你实现
it, You can't just implement description and
它,你不能只是描述和实现
expect it to work, You have to say, yes, and I implement
期望它去上班,你不得不说,是的,我实现
CustomStringConvertible by putting that on there,
CustomStringConvertible把,,
So give that a try, Go get your calculator and
所以给它一试,去把你的计算器和
put this colon CustomStringConvertible, And
把这个冒号CustomStringConvertible,
then, in your view controller somewhere, print out your
然后,在你的视图控制器,打印出你
CalculatorBrain with\(), See what you get, all right?
计算器并用\(),看看你,好吗?
Another really simple use of protocols is delegation, okay?
另一个很简单的使用的协议是代表团,好吗?
And it's really where we've all been leading up to here,
,这是真的,我们都在这里,
in terms of a use case of protocols, This is not gonna
一个用例的协议,这是不会的
use any of the other stuff I was talking about, generics or
使用任何其他的东西我在讲,泛型或
extensions, none of that, okay?
扩展,这些,好吗?
This is just the simplest possible use of protocols,
这只是最简单的使用协议,
although it does use Objective-C protocols
虽然它使用objective - c协议
because a lot of optional methods in these protocols,
因为很多可选的方法在这些协议,
But this is how we're gonna implement this MVC
但这就是我们要实现MVC
thing we talked about, which is blind, structured
我们讨论过,这是盲目的,结构化的
communication, The delegate and the data source, remember
沟通,委托和数据源,记住
that from lecture 2? This is how we're gonna implement it,
从讲座2吗?
we're gonna implement this with protocols, So here's how
我们会实现这个协议,这是如何
it plays out, to use protocols to do that delegation, First,
中,使用协议代表团,首先,
UIView thing, okay, like a ScrollView, for example,
UIView的事情,像一个滚动视图,例如,
or a TableView, which we'll talk about next week,
或视图,我们下周再谈,
It declares a protocol, which has all the will and
它声明一个协议,所有的意志和
should and did methods I was talking about,
应该和我谈论了方法,
So I will scroll to here, or should I allow scrolling in
所以我将滚动到这里,或者我应该允许滚动
this direction? Those kind of methods, it implements
这个方向?
a protocol that just has those methods listed in it,
协议中列出,只是这些方法,
It's gonna be an Objective-C protocol,
它会是一个objective - c协议,
they're almost all gonna be optional, all right? So it
他们几乎所有的可选的,对吧?
just declares that protocol, Then the view adds public API
只是宣布的协议,然后视图添加公共API
to itself, which is a weak property called delegate or
本身,这是一个软弱的属性称为委托或
sometimes data source, And that type is that protocol,
有时数据源,这类协议,
okay? So anything can be assigned to that var,
好吧?
as long as it implements that protocol, The view uses this
只要它实现了协议,使用这个视图
delegate property in itself to get the answer,
委托财产本身得到答案,
should I scroll here, and to tell people, I just did scroll
我应该滚动,并告诉人们,我只是滚动吗
here, okay? It sends those messages to the delegate,
在这里,好吗?
because the delegate implements, optionally,
因为委托实现,可选地,
the methods in that protocol so we can send it to them,
协议的方法,所以我们可以把这个表寄给他们,
If it has no delegate, if the delegate is nil,
如果它没有委托,委托是零,
because this weak delegate property, since it's weak,
因为这个弱委托财产,因为它是弱,
it has to be an optional, All weak properties are optional,
它必须是一个可选的,弱的所有属性都是可选的,
So it could be nil, And if it's nil,
所以它可能是零,如果是零,
then the ScrollView's just not gonna talk to a delegate,
然后滚动视图只是不会跟一个委托,
It's just not gonna ask it any questions or tell it anything,
它只是不会问任何问题或者告诉它,
Now, the controller declares that it implements that
现在,控制器宣称它实现
protocol, That's what it has to say,
协议,它说,
It has to say at the top, you know, if view, class UI view,
它说,你知道,如果视图,用户界面视图类,
class calculator view controller, whatever,
计算器视图控制器类,无论如何,
UIViewController comma UIScrollViewDelegate, So
逗号UIScrollViewDelegate ui
it says, I implement that, Then the controller sets
它说,我实现,那么控制器集
itself as the delegate of the view, which will be legal now
本身的代表观点,现在是合法的
because the controller claims to implement that protocol,
由于控制器实现声称协议,
So it can now be put in a var of type
所以现在可以放在一个var的类型
that protocol, And finally,
那个协议,最后,
the controller implements whatever methods it wants,
控制器实现任何方法,
Since they're probably mostly optional, it can just pick and
因为他们可能是可选的,它可以挑选
choose which ones it wants to,
选择哪一个它想要,
And those did and should methods will now start being
这些了,现在应该方法将开始
sent to it by the ScrollView or whatever, okay?
发送给它的滚动视图等等,好吗?
So now the view's hooked up to the controller,
现在视图的连接到控制器,
The view has no idea who he's talking to, All it knows about
视图不知道在跟谁说话,都知道
this delegate is that it implements those should and
这个委托是它实现了这些应该和
did things, That's all it knows,
做的事情,它知道,
so it's a completely generic and reusable view still,
这是一个完全通用的和可重用的视图,
But it can communicate with the controller, This mechanism
但它可以与控制器通信,这种机制
of delegation, you find it all throughout iOS,
在iOS的代表团,你会发现这一切,
Any complicated iOS object is gonna use delegation when it
任何复杂的iOS对象会使用代表团时
needs to talk back to its controller
需要反馈控制器
in a complicated way, This was all designed, though,
在一个复杂的方式,这是所有设计的,不过,
pre-Swift and pre-closures, things like that,
pre-Swift pre-closures,类似这样的事情,
A lot of times, a closure might be a better solution
很多时候,一个闭包可能是一个更好的解决方案
than delegation, So, delegation- a little bit of,
比代表团,代表团,一点点,
what do you call it, backwards compatibility thing,
你叫它什么,向后兼容性,
But you still gotta know it well if you're gonna do iOS,
但你仍然要知道如果你要做的iOS,
because it's just everywhere in iOS, By the way,
因为它只是在iOS,顺便说一下,
do not use delegation in your homework assignment three,
不要使用在你的作业三个代表团,
I think I might even have made it a required task,
我想我甚至可能使它所需的任务,
You can't do it, do not use delegation, I never
你不能这样做,不使用代表团,我从来没有
teach you anything after the assignment's already,
教你什么任务已经结束后,
you know, started, Delegation's not for
你知道的,开始的时候,代表团并不适合
assignment three, All right, so let's take a quick look at
作业三个,好吧,让我们看看
what this looks like code-wise for ScrollView, First,
这是什么样子在代码级别上滚动视图,首先,
ScrollView's going to have a var called delegate,
滚动视图有一个var叫委托,
It's gonna be of type UIScrollViewDelegate optional
它会UIScrollViewDelegate型可选的
because it's weak, The protocol UIScrollViewDelegate
因为它是弱,协议UIScrollViewDelegate
looks like this, It's got these optional functions,
是这样的,它有这些可选的功能,
like scrollViewDidScroll and
像scrollViewDidScroll和
give me the viewForZooming in the ScrollView,
给我viewForZooming滚动视图,
etc, Then the controller is gonna say, yeah, I implement
等,然后控制器会说,是的,我实现
UIScrollViewDelegate by doing the little or purple or
UIScrollViewDelegate通过小或紫色
blue or whatever code that is, And in viewDidLoad, the view
蓝色或任何代码,在viewDidLoad视图
controller's gonna say, ScrollView's delegate is me,
控制器会说,它的代表是我,
So ScrollView, please send me all those messages, And
所以滚动视图,请寄给我所有这些消息
then it would just implement whichever methods it wants,
然后它就会实现任何方法,
And we'll see this in the demo I'm gonna do today as well,
我们会看到今天的演示中我要做的,
All right, so that's it for delegation,
好了,这就是代表团,
Let's move on now to the first class that uses delegation,
现在让我们来看第一个类使用委托,
it's ScrollView, Before I talk about ScrollView,
滚动视图,在我谈论滚动视图,
I wanna show you a little bit how ScrollView works,
我想给你一点滚动视图是如何工作的,
this ancient video I have,
这个古老的视频我有,
This is like, I don't know, iPhone 1 or something, But
我不知道,这就像iPhone 1之类的,但是
if you look at the way it's scrolling,
如果你看看它的滚动,
it actually is very sophisticated,
它实际上是非常复杂的,
It can have a horizontally scrolling thing,
它可以有一个水平滚动,
like the stock charts, and
像股票图表,
inside of it, have vertically scrolling ScrollView,
它的内部,有垂直滚动滚动视图,
So that's ScrollViews inside ScrollViews, okay?
这是滚动视图内滚动视图?
And ScrollView's smart enough to know whether you're swiping
和它的足够聪明知道你刷
sideways or vertically to make it scroll, Now let's talk
横向或垂直滚动,现在让我们谈谈
about how you put something in a ScrollView so you can scroll
如何把东西放在一个滚动视图,以便您可以滚动
around in it, But you do it by adding subviews to it, So
在,但你通过添加子视图,所以
let's review how we add subviews to a normal view, So
让我们回顾一下我们如何添加子视图正常视图,所以
I create a view, like a logo view, And I set its frame,
我创建一个视图,就像一个标志来看,我设置它的框架,
which is where it's gonna be in its superview,
这就是它会在它的父视图,
And then I just add it to its superview, So here, I'm saying
然后我将它添加到它的父视图,这里,我说
view,addSubview(logo) view is probably the top-level view
看来,addSubview(商标)视图可能是顶层视图
in my view controller, Or we know that there's a var called
在我看来控制器,或者我们知道有一个var
view for that, So a ScrollView is similar, But
视图,因此滚动视图是相似的,但是
before you're doing all that, you're doing a very important
之前你做的这一切,你做的一个非常重要的
step, which is to set the contentSize of the scrollView,
步,设置contentSize滚动视图,
So this is a var contentSize, It's a CGSize,
这是一个var contentSize,CGSize,
And it's gonna be how big a space you're going to be
它会是你要多大的空间
scrolling over, So you've gotta set that first, It's
滚动,所以你得第一,
very important to set that first, But then, after that,
非常重要,首先,然后,之后,
you just addSubview, just like you did before,
你只是addSubview,就像以前一样,
So here, I added the, this logo view at 2700 across and
所以在这里,我添加了,2700,这个标志视图
50 down, And that's it, so now the ScrollView is
50了,就是这样,所以现在滚动视图
going to scroll around, Here, I added another one,
要滚动,在这里,我添加了另一个,
Let's add two views, okay, we got two views in there, And
让我们添加两个观点,好的,我们有两种观点,
now the ScrollView is just going to scroll around
现在,滚动视图滚动
on this content area, You see, it's just scrolling around,
在这个内容区域,你看,这只是滚动,
In fact, you'll even see the white of the content area
事实上,你甚至可以看到白色的内容区域
while you're scrolling around to do that, Now, of course,
当你在滚动,现在,当然,
you can reposition the views, Let's put this big
你可以重新定位观点,让我们把这个大
aerial view up in the corner, And
角落里的鸟瞰图,
then let's put the Stanford logo so that it overlaps it,
然后我们把斯坦福大学的标志,重叠,
And then we can always change our contentSize any time
然后我们可以改变我们的contentSize任何时间
we want to not have any extra space, right,
我们希望没有任何额外的空间,对吧,
and contain the whole thing, So if we do that, then,
包含整件事情,如果我们这样做,然后,
when we're scrolling around, we're not seeing
当我们四处滚动,我们没有看到
the white background there, So that's how ScrollView works,
白色背景,这就是滚动视图是如何工作的,
couldn't be simpler, It's all about that content size,
不能简单,都是关于内容的大小,
If you forget to set the content size,
如果你忘了设置内容大小,
scroll view will not work, If you remember nothing else from
滚动视图不会工作,如果你还记得什么
this lecture, remember that, Once it's scrolling around,
这节课,记住,一旦它滚动,
you can find out information about where it is,
你可以找到有关它的信息,
You can find out the upper left corner for
你可以找到的左上角
example of where the scroll view is, Using scrollView's
滚动视图的例子,使用它的
contentOffset point, it'll tell you the x and
内容偏移一点,它会告诉你x和
y of the upper left corner of where the thing is, You could
y的左上角,事情是这样的,你可以
also just say, where is the rectangle that is currently
也只是说,目前的矩形
showing the scrollView, where is that showing in the view
显示滚动视图,显示在视图中
behind that like aerial view of Stanford? But to do that,
背后的俯瞰斯坦福大学吗?
don't forget that those are different coordinate systems,
别忘了,这些都是不同的坐标系统,
They're different views so
他们不同的观点
they have different coordinate systems,
他们有不同的坐标系统,
So you have to convert, all right,
所以你必须转换,
You're gonna convert the scrollView's bounds, right,
你会把它的边界,对吧,
the scrollView's bounds,
它的边界,
that's in the scrollView's coordinate system, You're
在滚动视图的坐标系统,你
gonna convert that to the coordinate system of the view
将它转换为视图的坐标系统
like aerial, See, I'm doing aerial,convert up there,
像天线一样,看,我在做空中,转换,
converting that rectangle, Now why are those rectangles
将矩形,现在为什么这些矩形
not the same? Well, a lot of reasons,
不一样的吗?
One, you're panning around so it's always changing,
一个,你浏览所以总是改变,
Two, you might be zoomed, so it might be quite different,
2、你可能会放大,所以这可能是完全不同的,
If you're zoomed in on that scrollView than that little
如果你放大比那个小滚动视图
rectangle might represent a huge piece of aerial or it
矩形或者它可能代表一块巨大的天线
might represent a tiny, little piece of aerial, Who knows,
可能代表一个小型天线,谁知道呢,
So you're gonna use this method we already saw,
所以你要用这个方法我们已经看到,
We saw it when we were doing the drawing example,
我们看到它,当我们在做图的例子中,
I converted center from my super view down to my view
我从超视图转换中心我的观点
here, I'm just converting the bound to the scrollView, From
在这里,我只是将绑定到滚动视图,
the scrollView to whatever view there that I'm interested
滚动视图的任何观点,我很感兴趣
in, All right, Now,
好了,现在,
how do we create one of these things? Very straightforward,
我们如何创建一个这些东西?
We drag it out of the utilities area in storyboard,
我们拖出来公用事业领域的故事板,
It's just a view so you can do UIView, scrollView frame
它只是一个视图,这样你就可以做UIView,滚动视图框架
if you want, but 99% of the time we're pulling it out,
如果你愿意,但是99%的时间我们拉出来,
You can also pick a view that's already in your
你也可以选择一个已经在你的视图
storyboard and go up to Embed and say Embed In -> Scroll
故事板和去嵌入,嵌入在- >滚动
View, And it'll put it inside the scrollView, Okay, so
视图,它就会滚动视图内,所以
that's another way to do that, Then you just add whatever
这是另一个方法,那么你只需要添加
your too big view is, The view you wanna scroll around in,
你太大视图,视图你想滚动,
You just add it as a sub view of the scrollView, But
你只是把它作为一个滚动视图的子视图,但是
of course, you're not gonna forget to set the contentSize,
当然,你不会忘了设置contentSize,
Okay? And that's it, it's really quite simple to use,
好吧?
And you can scroll around in there programmatically,
你可以滚动以编程方式,
obviously, the user's gonna have their touch,
显然,用户会有联系,
And they can just pan around,
他们可以锅,
but you can do it too by saying scrollRectToVisible,
但它也可以通过scrollRectToVisible说,
and it'll take a rectangle and make it
和需要一个矩形
hopefully entirely fit on screen, It'll do the minimum
希望完全适合屏幕,它要做的最小值
amount of scrolling necessary to get that rectangle,
必要数量的滚动矩形,
on screen, You can do a lot of other things in scrollView,
在屏幕上,你可以做很多其他的事情在滚动视图,
I don't have time to talk about like controlling
我没有时间谈论喜欢控制
that behavior where it only scrolls vertically or
这种行为只有垂直滚动
horizontally and it'll kind of on first motion it'll figure
水平,它会在第一次运动图
out which one you mean and do that, You can flash
你指的是哪一个,这样做,你可以闪光
the scroll indicators when the thing appears on screen,
滚动指标当事情出现在屏幕上,
You can also offset the actual content that you're scrolling
你也可以抵消你滚动的实际内容
over by a little bit,
一点,
This happens a lot in navigation controllers,
这经常发生在导航控制器,
Sometimes the bar at the top, which is semi-opaque, or
有时顶部的酒吧,半透明,或
semi-transparent, is not transparent enough for
半透明的,不够透明
the application of the, whatever you're looking at in
的应用,无论你看
your scroll view, So you'll offset it a little bit,
你滚动视图,所以你会抵消一下,
the content you'll offset by that height of the, navigation
的内容你就会抵消,高度,导航
draw, So there's a whole bunch of stuff in there I can't
画,所以有很多东西我不能
really talk about, Another big piece of this is zooming,
真的谈,另外一个大的缩放,
So, we've talked about panning around in the scroll view but
所以,我们谈到了平移在滚动视图
you can also use your pinching to zoom in and
你也可以使用进行缩放
out, So zooming in and out, the way that works,
所以放大和缩小,作品的方式,
all UIViews have a property called their transform,
所有ui视图有一个属性称为他们的变换,
It's an affine transform which means it has translate, scale,
这是一个仿射变换这意味着它有翻译,,
and rotate, And when you pinch on a view,
和旋转,当你捏一个视图,
all it's doing is affecting the scale of its transform,
这是做的一切都是影响其变换,
does nothing else, Now that for most views, for
没有别的,现在大多数的观点,对吗
all views, that's going to scale the bits up, So
所有视图,将部分,规模
if you zoomed in really big, you'd have really big pixels,
如果你放大很大,你会有非常大的像素,
It would look really grainy, But if the view wants to,
它看起来很模糊,但如果想,
it can make it look really good after the zooming is
它可以让它看起来很好的在缩放
done, for example, UIImageView does that, If you're zooming
完成了,例如,UIImageView呢,如果你缩放
in on a UI image and its got more bits of resolution, it'll
在UI中形象和其有更多的分辨率,它会
show them to you as you zoom in, and you could do that, for
给你放大,你可以这样做,
example, with your calculator, If you had your calculator in
与你的计算器,如果你有计算器
a scroll view, which you're not going to,
滚动视图,你不会,
But if you did, if you had the graph part of it, you could,
但如果你做了,如果你有图的一部分,你可以,
when it pinched in, when it was done pinching, you could
当它了,做的时候捏,你可以
re-draw the graph to give it nice smooth curves, right, so
重新绘制图形给它平滑曲线,所以
it wouldn't be all pixelated, All right,
它不会是所有像素化,
I'll show you how to do that in the next slide, So,
我将向您展示如何做下一张幻灯片,所以,
two things about zooming in a scroll view though that you
两个事情缩放滚动视图不过你
have to know, One is you have to set the minimum and
要知道,一个是你必须设置最小和
maximum zoom scale, So that's how far you'll zoom in, and
最大缩放尺度,所以你会放大,多远
how far you're allowed to zoom out, And
你可以缩小多远,
by default these are 1,0 and 1,0, meaning no zooming in and
默认情况下这些都是1,0和1,0,没有放大和意义
no zooming out, So you have to set these to something, So
没有放大,所以你必须设置这些东西,所以
if you set the minimum zoom scale to 0,5,
如果你将最小缩放尺度设置为0,5,
means you'll zoom down to half its normal size,
意味着你会放大到正常大小的一半,
And if you set the maximum zoom scale to 2,0 it means
如果你设置最大缩放尺度为2,这意味着0
you're gonna zoom out to twice its normal size, All right, so
你会缩小到原来的两倍,所以
you can decide how much you want to let your users zoom in
你可以决定你想让你的用户放大
and out, The other piece is you need a delegate method,
,另一件是你需要一个委托方法,
Zooming does not work without delegation, And so
缩放不工作没有代表团等
you have to implement this delegate method called
你必须实现这个委托方法调用
viewForZooming(in scrollView) and all you have to do is
viewForZooming(滚动视图)和所有你要做的就是
return the view that's in the scroll view,
返回在滚动视图,视图
one of the subviews, the one that you're going to zoom on,
的子视图,你要放大,
And this is the one whose transform transformed,
这是一个转换的变换,
Of course you can zoom programmatically as well,
当然,你也可以通过编程方式放大,
It's not just pinching to zoom,
这不仅仅是进行缩放,
You can set the zoom scale, Here's some examples on how to
你可以在这里设置缩放尺度,对如何的一些例子
do that, So here I set my zoom scale to 1,2, now I'm gonna
这样做,这里我把缩放比例为1,2,现在我要吗
set it to 1,0, See it goes back to normal size,
将其设置为1,0,看到它回到正常大小,
1,2 I'm zoomed in 20% okay or same thing with rect, If I put
1、2我放大20%好或用矩形同样的事情,如果我把
a little rectangle right there and I say zoom to that rect
一个小矩形,我说变焦矩形
it's gonna zoom that rect out as big as it can be,
它会放大,矩形尽可能大,
Or if I had a rectangle that was bigger and
如果我有一个更大的矩形
I said zoom to rect it will zoom it down so
我说变焦矩形将变焦下来
the rectangle fits, Okay it's going to do the minimum
矩形,好的要做最低
zooming to get that rectangle on screen,
缩放得到矩形在屏幕上,
There's lot of of other delegate methods,
还有很多其他的委托方法,
at least a dozen more besides that view for zooming and
至少十几个更多的缩放和除此之外的观点
scrollView, For example, if you wanted to do the thing
滚动视图,例如,如果你想做的事情
where you zoomed in and then you wanted to re-draw
你先放大,然后你想吗
to get rid of the pixelation, you would implement
的像素,你会实现
scrollViewDidEndZooming with view atScale, And
与视图atScale scrollViewDidEndZooming,
this will tell you when the pinching has stopped and
这将告诉你什么时候捏已经停止
now you can re-draw, Of course if you re-draw by
现在你可以重新绘制,当然如果你重新绘制
the way at the new scale, you're gonna reset
在新规模的方式,你会重置
your transform, the view's transform,
你的改变,视图的变换,
back to the identity transform, Otherwise, you'll
身份转换,否则,你会
both drawing it scaled and it will be scaled because you're
都画它了,因为你
affine transform is well pixelated too, So, you don't
仿射变换是像素化了,所以,你不喜欢
want both of those things going on at the same time,
希望这些事情同时,
So you reset, you would reset your transform here,
所以你重置,重置你的变换,
Okay, so the rest of this is going to be demo, so
好的,所以这将是演示,剩下的
let me just talk about what's coming up here,
让我谈谈即将发生的事,
The demo I'm gonna do is a Scroll View Demo, obviously,
演示我要做的是一个滚动视图演示,显然,
I'm gonna show you how to do that,
我将告诉你如何做到这一点,
I'll show you some other things too, like extensions,
我将向您展示一些其他事情上,比如扩展,
things like that, On Friday we have
周五,我们有
Instruments, Okay, performance testing, Really important if
工具,性能测试非常重要
you want to do the extra credit in Assignment 3,
你想做作业3中的额外学分,
which is a good one,
这是一个好一个,
you have to figure out why your calculator,
你必须弄清楚为什么你的计算器,
graphing thing doesn't perform as well as you'd like,
图形的事情不会执行以及你想,
On Monday, Assignment 3, what you're working on now,
周一,任务3,现在你所从事的工作,
your graphing calculator is due, before lecture, And
你的图形计算器是由于,在讲座之前,和
then the topic on Monday is going to be multi-threading,
然后周一的主题将是多线程,
We're gonna take the demo we're doing today,
我们要把我们今天正在做的演示,
which is going to be very sluggish,
这是非常缓慢,
and we're going to make it perform a lot better using
我们会让它更好用
multi-threading, On Wednesday, we're going to go into
多线程,周三,我们将进入
TableView, really important part of the UIKit,
TableView非常UIKit的重要组成部分,
There will be an assignment, a TableView assignment that goes
将会有一个任务,一个TableView作业,
out on Wednesday, It'll be due the next Wednesday, And
周三,它会由于下周三,
there's no more reading assignments, I can tell from
没有更多的阅读作业,我可以告诉
talking to some of you that you didn't read any of
谈论一些你没读过
them very closely, And you know, I don't quiz you on it,
他们非常密切,你知道,我没有测试你,
I don't test you on it because it's kind of up to you how
我不测试你的它,因为它是你怎么做
much you wanna learn in this class,
你想学习这门课,
It's just one of those things where whatever you put into
这只是其中之一,无论你投入
it is what you get out of it, But
这是你得到的,但是
I really encourage you to at least go through the parts
我真的建议你至少经历的部分
in there that you don't understand, and
在那里,你不懂,
be cognizant of the fact, I don't really understand this,
被认识到的事实,我真的不理解这一点,
Okay, because then when you graduate from this class,
好吧,因为当你从这个类毕业,
which is, you know, you're getting started with iOS in
这是,你知道,你开始使用iOS在吗
this class, When you graduate from it you'll know,
这个类,毕业的时候你就会知道,
okay that's something I gotta go back and
好吧,我得回去
really understand better, All right, okay so
真正理解好,好,好
this demo is going to be, again, fresh start,
这演示将是全新的开始,
So I'm gonna create a new Xcode project in single view
所以我要单视图中创建一个新的Xcode项目
application, I'm gonna call it Cassini,
应用程序,我将称之为“卡西尼”号,
cuz we're gonna do some stuff with the images that came out
因为我们要做一些东西的图片出来了
back from Cassini probe that went off to Saturn,
从卡西尼号土星探测器,去,
And I'm gonna put it in the same place I put all my maps,
我要把它放在同一个地方我把我所有的地图,
home directory Developer, And here it is I'm gonna move
主目录开发人员,这是我要搬家
xcassets and the AppDelegate and the LaunchScreen out
xcassets和在AppDelegate LaunchScreen出来
of the way again, I'm actually not going to move info,plist
再次,我真的不会移动信息,plist
out though, We are going to be looking at that today, So
不过,我们会看看,今天,
we're gonna put these in Supporting Files,
我们要把这些支持文件,
Now, I showed you last time how we can rename
现在,我给你最后一次如何重命名
a ViewController, if it's got like a generic name like this,
ViewController,如果它有像这样的通用名称,
You know, another thing we could do to this
你知道,我们可以做的另一件事
ViewController, is just delete it, So I'm just gonna go here,
ViewController,就删除它,所以我要去这里,
right click on it, and delete it, And remove all references
右键单击它,并删除它,并删除所有引用
to it and I'm gonna go to my storyboard right here, which
,我要去我的故事板,哪个
still has this ViewController, And by the way, if I go look
还有这个ViewController,顺便问一下,如果我去看
at the identity inspector here for that ViewController,
在这里的身份检查员ViewController,
It's still trying to be class ViewController,
它仍在努力是ViewController类,
even though I deleted that from my app, all right,
尽管我从应用程序,删除,好吧,
But I'm gonna fix that by just deleting that from my
但我还是要解决,只需删除从我
storyboard, All right, so now no ViewController anywhere,
故事板,所以现在没有ViewController,
Now, I do need a view controller for my app and
现在,我需要为我的应用程序和一个视图控制器
it's gonna be called ImageViewController,
它会被称为ImageViewController,
It's going to be a generic, reusable MVC for showing
这将是一个通用的、可重用的MVC显示
an image, Whenever I build an MVC, I always wanna see if I
一个图像,每当我构建一个MVC,我总是想看看我
can build a nice generic reusable one because then
可以构建一个通用的可重用因为呢
maybe I can use it in some other app that I'm building,
也许我可以使用它在其他一些应用程序,我是建筑,
And also it gives me the discipline as an API
它也给我纪律作为一个API
designer to think about my public and private API even,
设计师思考我的公共和私有API,
So, let's go ahead and do that, let's create a new file,
所以,让我们继续这样做,让我们创建一个新文件,
Coco Touch Class of course, and we'll call it
可可触摸类当然,我们叫它
ImageViewController, it's a subclass of UIViewController,
ImageViewController,ui的一个子类,
Okay, very carefully here,
好的,小心,
I do not wanna put this at the top level, I wanna put it down
我不希望把这个在顶层,我想放下
in here where the rest of my files are, All right so
在这里我剩下的文件在哪里,好吧
I got my ImageViewController here, I don't need for
我ImageViewController这里,我不需要
now anyway, any of the ViewController lifecycle, I'm
现在不管怎样,任何ViewController生命周期的,我
also not going to segue from this MVC, So I don't need any
也不会从这个MVC segue,所以我不需要任何
of that, I actually I'm going to be segueing to it however,
,我我要segue然而,
because it's a nice reusable image showing things,
因为它是一个可重用的图像显示,
So as you can imagine I might want to be segueing to it any
所以你可以想象我想可能segue任何
time I want to show an image, When I have a new class like
我想显示一个图像,当我有一个新类
this one the first things I like to do is think about what
这一次我想做的第一件事是想想
is my model? Because the model is what this MVC does?
我的模型吗?
So if I can determine what the model is, it'll help me
如果我可以确定模型是什么,它会帮助我
think clearly about what this MVC is all about,
清楚地思考这MVC是什么,
And so this shows an image, so
这显示一个图像
I'm gonna have my model, I'm gonna have it be public so
我要有我的模型,我将把它是公开的
other people can set my model, and I'm going to have it be
别人可以设置我的模型,我将拥有它
a URL of an image, Because what does my MVC does?
一个图像的URL,因为我的MVC什么?
It shows an image, That's what it is, an image shower, So,
它显示一个图像,这是它是什么,一个图像洗澡,所以,
it seems like having a URL of an image would be a good model
似乎有一个图像的URL是一个很好的模型
for it, Now, let's go back to our storyboard here and
,现在,让我们回到我们的故事板在这里
create an MVC for this thing, So I'm just gonna grab
创建一个MVC因这事,所以我要抓住
a View Controller, Drag it out here, Gonna go up to
一个视图控制器,拖出来,要去
the identity inspector, again, and I'm gonna set it to be
身份检查,再一次,我要把它
an ImageViewController, right? Now,
一个ImageViewController,对吧?
I could start building my UI here by dragging more things
我可以开始构建UI这里通过拖放更多东西
in, but I thought it might be valuable a little bit, to show
,但我认为这可能是有价值的,
you how to build some UI in code, It's gonna be simple,
如何构建一些UI代码,它会是简单的,
but we'll build some UI in code, And what my UI here is
但我们会构建一些UI代码,这里我的UI
gonna be at the beginning is just an ImageViewController or
会一开始只是一个ImageViewController或
a UIImageView, right? I'm just going to show an image using
UIImageView ?
UIImageView, this class UIImageView, By the way,
UIImageView,这类UIImageView,顺便说一下,
one thing that's missing here, you can tell by this warning,
一个失踪的事情,你可以告诉这个警告,
Let's click on this warning and see what it says,
让我们点击这个警告,看看它说,
It says ImageViewController is unreachable,
它说ImageViewController是遥不可及的,
Remember that? There's no way to get to this, That's because
还记得吗?
there is no arrow that goes into this anywhere,
没有箭头进入这个地方,
If I were to run this app, it would crash and
如果我运行这个程序,它会崩溃
say, there's no initial View Controller, So,
说,没有初始视图控制器,因此,
how do you set the initial View Controller? Well,
如何设置初始视图控制器?
you pick the View Controller you want to be the initial one
你选择你想要的视图控制器的初始
and you go over here to the Attributes Inspector because
你到这里属性检查器,因为
it's an attribute of that View Controller, And down here
它的一个属性视图控制器,
under View Controller right after its title is, is Initial
在视图控制器对其标题后,是最初的
View Controller, So, I click that and look what happened,
视图控制器,因此,我点击看看发生了什么事,
You got the little entry arrow there, So
你有小箭头,
now when this thing run, it's gonna jump right into this
现在,当运行,它会直接到这个
View Controller, Which is where we wanted to start,
视图控制器,这是我们想要开始,
Eventually we're gonna have other MVCs, but
最终我们会有其他mvc,但是
we'll start with this one, All right,
我们将从这个,好吧,
back to my ImageViewController here, I said I wanted to
回到我ImageViewController这里,我说我想
build its UI in code, I know I need ImageView so
构建UI的代码,我知道我需要ImageView
I'm just gonna start right off with private var imageView:
我要开始马上与私人var imageView:
is a UIImageView, And in fact, I'm gonna
是一个UIImageView,事实上,我要吗
create it right here, There's no reason not just to say,
创建它,不仅没有理由说,
this, it's going to create it with basically CGRect zero,
基本上,它将创建与CGRect中0,
This is just like saying frame: CGRect,zero,
这就像说框架:CGRect中,零,
it's exactly the same as doing that, but you know we don't
这样做完全一样,但你知道我们不喜欢
need that extra code there, So now I've created this image
需要额外的代码,现在我创建了这个形象
view, it's in the upper left hand corner of whatever its
看来,在无论它的左上角
super view is, it's not in any super view yet, and
超级的观点是,没有在任何超级看来,
it's of zero zero size, So it's not that useful, but
00大小的,所以并不是很有用,但是
of course, as soon as I set an image in it, I will resize it
当然,当我设置一个图片,我将调整它
to fit that image, And speaking of setting an image
适应这一形象,说到一个图像
in it, I imagine that when I set an image in my imageView,
在这篇文章中,我想,当我在imageView设置一个图片,
I'm gonna need to do things like change the the frame,
我需要做事情喜欢改变帧,
of my imageView, and things like that,
imageView之类的东西,
So I'm gonna create a little private var here,
所以我要创建一个私有变量,
called image, which is gonna be a UIImage and
称为图像,这是将是一个用户界面图像
it's gonna be computed and it's gonna have a get and
它会计算,它会有一个和
a set so that every time I get or set the image,
一组,这样每次我得到或一组图片,
I can do other stuff, Okay, this is a really kind of
我可以做其他的东西,好吧,这是一种真正的
simple clean way to keep, you know to do ancillary things
简单的清洁方法,你知道做辅助的事情
when you're settings and getting some piece of data,
当你设置和获取一些数据,
So, for example, when I set this image right here,
所以,例如,当我把这个形象,
I'm going to set the imageView's image to be equal
我要设置imageView相等的形象
to that new value of course, That's the primary thing if I
新值,当然,如果我的首要事情
wanna set my image, I need to set it in my imageView,
想我的形象,我需要把它在我imageView,
So this var right here is just the image that this imageView
所以这里的var是图像,这种图像
is showing, But then also like I said,
显示,但后来也就像我说的,
I want to set my imageView's size to fit this new image,
我想把我imageView的大小以适应这个新形象,
In fact, there happens to be a method called sizeToFit in
事实上,碰巧有一个方法叫做sizeToFit
imageView that will cause it to size its frame to
imageView将导致其大小帧
fit whatever image is inside of it,
适合任何图像内部,
So it's nice that it had that this nice method for
所以很高兴,这个好方法
me right here, If I control click on it, you can read it,
我在这里,如果我控制点击它,你可以阅读它,
See that's what it says,
看到这就是它说,
And then how about getting it? Well, I'm just gonna return
然后把它怎么样?
the imageView's image in this case, Okay, so this
imageView的形象在这种情况下,这
is a var and it's computed, so there's no storage, And
是一个var计算,所以没有存储,然后呢
actually I'm doing the storage here in the imageView, Now,
实际上我做imageView存储在这里,现在,
this is giving me an error right here, And the error it's
这是给我一个错误,错误的
giving me is that I need to unwrap this, Well,
给我,我需要打开这个,好吧,
that's because this image right here is an optional,
这是因为这里的形象是一个可选的,
Cuz imageViews don't have to have an image,
因为imageview不需要一个图像,
they could be empty at the time,
他们可以是空的,
Now I could unwrap this here, but I'm thinking,
现在我可以打开这里,但我想,
you know what? I want my UI to be able to be showing no image
你知道吗?
at some point, That's perfectly reasonable, So
在某种程度上,这是完全合理的
instead, I'm gonna change this to be optional, So this
相反,我要改变这是可选的,所以这一点
image var is optional, it can be nil, And when I do that I
形象var是可选的,它可以是零,当我这样做
wanna make sure that I can say imageView,image = newValue,
要确保我可以说imageView、图像= newValue,
is that gonna work if newValue is nil? Yes, it is because
是要工作如果newValue nil ?
we know that this imageView's image is itself an optional,
我们知道这个imageView的形象本身就是一个可选的,
The imageView might have no image at this time,
imageView可能没有图像,
It's perfectly fine, Okay, everybody cool, understand
很好,好吧,大家都冷静,理解
what I did there? It's just a code organization thing,
我在那里做了什么吗?
it just keeps me from having to, you know,
它只是让我不必,你知道,
be resizing this fit somewhere else, Or to be putting
调整这个适合其他地方,或者是把
in some other part of my code that makes no sense, Here it
在其他一些我的部分没有任何意义的代码,在这里
makes sense because here's where I'm setting my image,
是有意义的,因为在这里我设置我的形象,
All right, let's now put this imageView into
好了,现在让我们把这个imageView
our view hierarchy in code, I told you we were gonna do
我们在代码视图层次,我告诉你我们要做的
our UI with code, Let's do it, We're gonna say viewDidLoad is
我们的UI代码,让我们这样做,我们会说许多
a good place to do this because we know that by
这样做是因为我们知道的好地方
the time viewDidLoad happens, we're fully initialized,
viewDidLoad发生的时候,我们完全初始化,
All our outlets are set,
我们所有的网点设置,
We've been prepared if someone's segueing to us,
我们已经准备好如果有人segue到我们,
We're in a really good state right now to add more things
我们现在处于很好的状态来添加更多的事情
to our UI, And I'm gonna do that just by saying view,
我们的UI,我要做的只是说的观点,
remember that the special bar in View Controller which is
记住特别的酒吧在视图控制器
the top level view, AddSubview my imageView,
AddSubview imageView顶级视图,
okay? So I'm just putting it on there,
好吧?
It'll either be zero zero size or if someone set my imageURL,
它会是00大小或如果有人把我imageURL,
then it might be sized to fit or whatever,
那么它可能大小适合,
Okay, now what happens if someone sets my imageURL?
好了,现在如果有人集我imageURL吗?
I better set this image, okay? And we know a good way to do
我最好把这个图片,好吗?
that, right? So our property observer here on our model,
,对吧?
any time someone sets our model, First I'm gonna
任何时候有人集我们的模型,首先我要
actually clear out whatever image I have, And then I'm
实际上清除任何图像,然后我
gonna put the fetching of an image in another method,
将图像的获取在另一种方法,
Remember that this imageURL might be an Internet URL and
记住,这imageURL可能是一个URL和互联网
this might be a slow Internet, this might take a long time,
这可能是一个缓慢的互联网,这可能需要很长时间,
So I'm gonna put it all off into this other function here,
所以我要把它到另一个函数,
private function, fetchImage,
私有函数,fetchImage,
And it's gonna do the image fetching, So
要做图像抓取,所以
how do we fetch an image from a URL, all right?
我们如何从一个URL获取图像,对吧?
It's actually remarkably easy,
其实非常简单,
First, I'm gonna make sure that I have a URL to fetch,
首先,我要确保我有一个URL获取,
I'm gonna say, if I can let a url equal our imageURL,
我想说,如果我可以让一个url imageURL相等,
that's our model, okay? If I can get my imageURL there,
这是我们的模型?
then I'm going to let the contents of that URL, so I'm
然后我要让那个URL的内容,所以我
gonna go out in the Internet and get the contents of it,
要在互联网和它的内容,
I'm gonna let that equal Data(contentsOf: url),
我要让这等于数据(contentsOf:url),
So data is that bag of bits, thing I told you about
所以数据袋位,我告诉你
a few lectures ago, And it has a really cool initializer
几年前的一个讲座,一个很酷的初始值设定项
which is load up your bag of bits with whatever's at this
与任何比特加载你的包在这吗
URL on the Internet, Now, this has an error right here, And
URL在互联网上,现在,这里有一个错误
the error is that this throws,
这个错误抛出,
because that URL might not point to something, or
因为URL可能不会点东西,或者
it might be a malformed URL, or it might be a URL to some,
这可能是一个畸形的URL,或者对某些人来说,这可能是一个URL
you know, bad data or something like that,
你知道,坏数据之类的,
So, if I look at this error here, it's complaining about
所以,如果我看这个错误,抱怨
the immutable, But it's also saying this call can throw,
不可变的,但它也是说这叫可以扔,
but is not marked with a try and
但不显著的尝试
the error is not handled, Now here, someone's asking me to
错误不是处理,现在,有人问我的
show this imageURL, I suppose I could catch that error and
显示这个imageURL,错误,我想我能赶上
like put up an alert saying,
喜欢把一个警告说,
here was the reason I couldn't show your, display your image,
这是我不能展示你的原因,显示您的图片,
But I'm just going to instead use try, with a question mark,
但是我要用试,一个问号,
and if I can't get it, then I just won't show it, Which is
如果我不能得到它,那么我就不会表现出来,这是
probably not that great but it's good enough for a demo,
可能不是很大,但足够的演示,
So now as soon as I put try question mark here, this is no
现在只要我试着问号,这是否定的
longer going to be of type data, It's gonna be what type?
时间类型的数据,它会是什么样?
Yeah, it's optional, See, it's an optional data because if it
是的,它是可选的,看到的,因为如果它是一个可选的数据
throws, it can come back nil, All right, since this is
抛出,它可以返回nil,好吧,既然这是
optional, I'm gonna say if I can let the imageData equal to
可选的,我想说如果我能让imageData等于
the contents of that URL, Then, now I can create
该URL的内容,那么,现在我可以创建
the UIImage with that and sure enough my image which is this
的用户界面图像,果然我的形象是这样的
var right here is gonna be equal to UIImage, And image,
var是会等于界面图像,图像,
we all know about Image named, but there's also Image,
我们都知道图片命名,但是也有图片,
with the imageData, So if you have the actual JPEG data or
imageData,所以如果你有实际的JPEG数据或
whatever, you can make an image out of that,
无论如何,你可以做一个图像,
And of course, when I do image = UIImage here,
当然,当我做图像=用户界面图像,
it's gonna go down here to this setter,
它会去下面这个setter,
It's gonna set that image in the UIImageView,
它会设置UIImageView形象,
Which we added as a subView and then it's gonna size to
我们作为子视图添加然后它会大小
fit that imageView and show it to us, all right?
适合imageView和展示给我们,好吗?
Okay, now, there's only one problem with this,
好了,现在,只有一个问题,
one thing I don't like about this, Which is well, let's do
有一件事我不喜欢,这是我们做的
one other thing too, I'm gonna go to viewDidLoad here and
另一件事,我要去viewDidLoad这里
have it do a demo URL, so we can see,
让它做一个演示网址,所以我们可以看到,
I'm gonna set my own imageURL equal to and
我要设置自己的imageURL等于
I have these demo URLs here, Okay, it's this little thing
我这里有这些演示url,这个小东西
right here, Copy that in, These demo URLs have a for
在这里,复制,在这些演示的url
example, a little Stanford URL right here and
这里的例子,斯坦福URL
also some NASA ones which we'll be doing next time,
我们会做一些NASA的下一次,
But I'm just gonna use this Stanford URL right here, So
但是我要用这个斯坦福URL,所以
our imageURL is DemoURL,stanford,
我们的imageURL DemoURL,斯坦福大学,
What I don't like about the way we've written this code
我不喜欢我们写这段代码的方式
though is here in viewDidLoad, I'm setting my imageURL to
虽然是在中大,我设置imageURL
stanford, That's gonna go up here and
斯坦福大学,会在这里
cause this fetchImage to immediately happen,
因为这fetchImage立即发生,
Which is gonna go out in the Internet and grab this image,
这是要在互联网和抓住这张图片,
So as soon viewDidLoad happens,
所以就viewDidLoad一切发生的时候,
man, I'm not on the Internet getting that thing, And
人,我不是在互联网上得到的东西,和
that's probably not something you wanna do, why wouldn't
这可能不是你想做的事,为什么不
you, Imagine this MVC which is supposed to be reusable was in
你想象一下MVC,应该是可重用的
a tab bar, okay, All of the MVCs that are in the tab bar,
标签栏,所有的mvc的标签栏,
they're all created in viewDidLoaded even before
他们都在viewdidload创建之前
any of them are shown, So, if I had a tab bar that had five
其中任何一个,所以,如果我有一个五个标签栏
image view controllers right here, they'd all be off on
图像视图控制器,他们应该都在
the Internet loading things, I might not click on any of
网络加载的东西,我可能不会点击任何
them, And I wasted the cellular data
他们,我浪费了蜂窝数据
plan of my user, all right,
计划我的用户,
So I really only wanna go fetch this URL when this
所以我真的只想拿来当这这个URL
view controller is going to appear on screen for sure, So
视图控制器将会出现在屏幕上,所以
can anyone think of where I would put that instead of in
谁能想到我将,而不是在哪里
viewDidLoad there? Different view controller lifecycle
viewDidLoad吗?
method, How about viewWillAppear?
方法,那些怎么样?
Super,viewWillAppear, So
超级,那些,所以
I'm going to do the actual fetching in viewWillAppear,
我要做实际的获取进行处理,
Now, I wanna do this, no? Okay, there's another problem
现在,我想做这个,不是吗?
though, What if I'm already onscreen and
不过,如果我已经在屏幕上
someone sets my image? Then I can't do it in viewWillAppear,
有人集我的形象吗?
I've gotta do it right away, So I can kind of
我必须这么做,所以我可以
really just want to delay doing it to viewWillAppear
只是想拖延做那些
if I'm not on screen already, So what I'm gonna do up here
如果我不是在屏幕上,所以我要做什么
with my imageURL up here is I'm just gonna check and
和我imageURL我要检查和
see if I'm currently on screen and if I am, so
看看我现在在屏幕上,如果我这样
I'm gonna say if my view,window is not nil,
我想说如果我看来,窗口不是零,
then I'm gonna go fetch this image right away, okay, So
然后我要拿这张照片,所以
view, remember that's the var that's the top level thing,
看来,记住,是顶级的var,
Window is a var that is in all UI views which tells
窗口是一个var在这告诉所有UI视图
you the window it's in, And if you don't have a window,
你的窗口,如果你没有一个窗口,
it means you're not on screen, If you do have a window,
这意味着你不是在屏幕上,如果你有一个窗口,
you are on screen, So if my view,window is not nil,
你在屏幕上,所以,如果我看来,窗口不是零,
then I'm on screen, I'm gonna go ahead and fetch,
然后我在屏幕上,我要去取回,
Otherwise I'm not gonna fetch, And instead down here in
否则我不会卖,而不是这里
viewWillAppear, I'm gonna say if my image is nil, So
那些,我想说如果我的形象是零,所以
if I don't have an image yet so far, then go fetch it, So
如果我还没有一个图像到目前为止,然后再取
you see how the combination of these two things is going to
你看看这两个东西会的结合
wait to fetch it until view will appear, Unless I'm
等到取回它视图将出现,除非我
already on screen, then it'll fetch it right away, So
已经在屏幕上,然后马上取回
that's at least delaying it,
至少推迟,
So now if I were in tab bars, when I clicked on the tab,
现在如果我在标签栏,当我点击选项卡,
viewWillAppear would happen and I would load up, And
那些我将负载,会发生
if I did something that caused the image to change, it would
如果我做了一些导致图像变化
change right away, cuz I'd be visible, If I went offscreen,
改变,因为我是可见的,如果我在私生活方面,
then clicked on another tab, my image was changed,
然后点击另一个选项卡,我的形象发生了变化,
it wouldn't change, When I click on it,
它不会改变,当我点击它,
then it would go get it from the Internet,
然后它会从互联网上得到它,
So, I'm minimizing the amount of data plan usage
所以,我计划使用的数据量最小化
if the person's going, doing it over cell,
如果这个人,做细胞,
Okay, so, I think we got everything we need here to
好,所以,我认为我们能得到我们想要的一切
make this work, Let's try running, let's go on an iPhone
做这个工作,让我们尝试跑步,让我们继续iPhone
7, Hopefully our network works on this laptop here, Okay, so,
7日,希望我们的网络工作这个笔记本,好了,所以,
it comes up here, and it's not showing, Where is our image?
谈到这里,它不显示,我们的形象在哪里?
We don't have any image, Well, I think I see something in
我们没有图片,我觉得我看到的东西
the console down here, Let's see what that says, It says,
控制台下面,让我们看看说,它说,
App Transport Security has blocked a cleartext HTTP,
应用交通安全已经阻止了明文HTTP、
hm, It's insecure, of course, we know HTTP is insecure,
嗯,这是不安全的,当然,我们知道HTTP是不安全的,
HTTPS is secure, It says, temporary exceptions can be
HTTPS是安全的,它说,可以暂时的异常
configured via your app's Info,plist file, Luckily,
通过应用程序的配置信息,plist文件,幸运的是,
I didn't move my Info,plist into Supporting Files,
我没有动信息,plist支持文件,
cuz I knew this was gonna happen, obviously, So
因为我知道这是可能发生的,很明显,所以
what's going on here?
这是怎么回事?
Well, if you look at the URL that we're trying to load,
好吧,如果你看看URL,我们试图加载,
this Stanford URL, see it's an insecure HTTP URL,
斯坦福大学的网址,看到这是一个不安全的HTTP URL,
And by default, iOS does not let you load those up,
iOS,默认情况下,不让你加载,
You have to say that you're willing to load those up
你说你愿意加载这些
untrusted URLs and you do that with this Info,plist,
不可信的url和你用这个信息,plist,
So what is an Info,plist? It's really just a list of some
那么什么是信息,plist ?
settings, some configurations, For example, it shows, will
设置,一些配置,例如,它表明,
you run in portrait mode? Will you run in landscape left?
你在肖像模式下运行?
In landscape right? Those kinds of things,
在景观对吧?
It's really kind of runtime configuration, how your app
真正的运行时配置,如何你的应用
will run, So we can add this App Transport Security
将运行,所以我们可以添加这个程序传输安全
that we need right here by right-clicking, okay,
我们需要在这里单击右键,
we right-click, Pay attention here, cuz you're gonna need to
我们右键单击,注意这里,因为你会需要
do this probably, in a, maybe in a future homework, But
可能这样做,在一个,也许在以后的作业,但
we're gonna right-click and pick Add Row,
我们要右键单击并选择添加一行,
So that's gonna add a row, Oops, we don't wanna add
这是要添加一行,哎呀,我们不想添加
a row there, sorry, That added a row to our support interface
一行,对不起,添加一行对我们支持的接口
configuration, >> So
配置> >
we wanna be not selecting that, and do Add Row, And
我们要不要选择,并添加行,
if you go look in Add Row, right near the top is App
如果你去看添加行,顶部是应用
transport security settings, You see it right there? So
交通安全设置,你看到它在这里吗?
I'm gonna click on that then I'm gonna open the security
我要点击,然后我要打开安全
settings, Don't forget to open those settings and
设置,别忘了这些设置和开放
then hit plus which will add a security setting and
然后点击+将添加一个安全设置和
here you can see the options, And
在这里你可以看到选项
we want the one which is allow arbitrary loads,
我们希望的是允许任意加载,
We'll allow any HTTP URL to be loaded and we're gonna go over
我们将允许任何HTTP URL加载和我们要复习
here and say that that is yes, So allows arbitrary loads,
在这里说,那是肯定的,所以允许任意加载时,
yes, okay? So we just add this to our Info,plist,
是的,好吗?
now when we run our app, we've given permission, essentially,
当我们运行我们的应用程序,我们允许,从本质上讲,
for the app to load these http non-S URLs,
应用程序加载这些http non-S url,
Okay, there we go, look at that, woo hoo!
好了,好了,看看,呜呼!
We got Stanford, and we can even rotate,
我们得到了斯坦福大学,我们甚至可以旋转,
Good, now of course we can't see the whole image here and
好,当然,我们不能看到整个图像
we can't zoom in, It would be nice to be able to zoom in,
我们不能放大,最好是能够放大,
For that we obviously need a scroll view, So
我们显然需要一个滚动视图,所以
how are we going to put a scroll view in here? Well,
我们将如何把一个滚动视图?
this is a good opportunity to show you mixing code for
这是一个很好的机会给你混合代码
doing your views in code, with doing it in the storyboard,
在代码视图,在故事板中,
So I'm gonna put my Scroll View in the storyboard, and
所以我要把我的故事板中的滚动视图,和
we'll leave the image view in code, Okay, so you see them
我们会把图像视图代码,好吧,你看到它们
both working together, So to put a Scroll View here in
都在一起工作,所以,给一个滚动视图
my storyboard, I'm going to just search for
我的故事板,我要寻找
Scroll View down here in the utilities window, there it is,
滚动视图下面的工具窗口,在这里,
I'm gonna drag out a scroll view, here it is,
我要拖出一个滚动视图,在这里,
I'm gonna use the blue lines to put it in the whole,
我要用蓝线在整个,
filling my whole, MVC here, without even any borders,
填满我的整个,MVC,甚至没有任何边界,
Then I'm gonna use this little reset to suggested
然后我要用这个小复位
constraints, you remember that?
约束,您还记得吗?
To have it do the auto layout for me,
对我来说做自动布局,
Then I'm actually gonna go up to the size inspector,
然后我会去检查大小,
right here, and click on it to double-check what it did,
在这里,点击它仔细检查它,
in terms of constraints, And sure enough,
的限制,果然,
it's done exactly the constraints I want, all right?
完成了完全约束的我想要的,对吧?
So we have this, We wanna talk to the scroll view,
所以我们有这个,我们想跟滚动视图,
of course we need an outlet to it, So, let's get our
当然,我们需要一个出口,所以,让我们把我们的
controller on screen at the same time here and let's
控制器在屏幕上同时让我们在这里
control drag, I'm gonna put it to scroll view down here by
控制拖,我要把它滚动视图下面
the image view, So let's control drag right into our
图像视图,我们拖到我们的控制
code right there, It's an outlet, get to scroll view,
代码,这是一个出口,滚动视图,
notice it's weak, We talked about why our
注意到它的软弱,我们谈论我们的原因
outlets are weak, I'm gonna call this outlet scrollView,
网点软弱,我要叫这个插座滚动视图,
Cuz that's what it is, Var scrollView right there, Now,
因为这是它是什么,Var滚动视图,现在,
I want to integrate the image view into the scroll view,
我想将图像视图集成到滚动视图,
so I'm just going to, when the scroll view gets set,
所以我要当滚动视图集,
I'm just gonna add that image view as a sub view,
我要添加图像视图的子视图,
Okay, and now I don't need to do that in viewDidLoad,
好吧,现在我在viewDidLoad不需要这样做,
Where is viewDidLoad? Okay, don't need to do adding
viewDidLoad在哪?
the image view as a sub view of our top
图像视图的子视图的顶部
level view because now I'm adding it as a sub view of
水平的观点,因为现在我添加的子视图
the scroll view, all right? Make sense? So,
滚动视图?
let's see if that just works, That should just work,
看看工作,应该工作,
Yeah, it's good, You should all be thinking about,
是的,这很好,你都应该考虑,
hm, why wouldn't that work? I'm gonna ask you why it's not
嗯,为什么不工作?
working in a second, All right, here it is! It looks
在第二个工作,好吧,在这儿!
like it works, Let's scroll, we can't scroll around, Why?
喜欢它的作品,滚动,我们不能滚动,为什么?
I know I put a scroll view in there, How come the scroll
我知道我放了一个滚动视图,怎么滚动
view's not scrolling? Anyone have an idea? Okay, the,
看来不是滚动吗?
he's saying the the two variables,
他说这两个变量,
the zooming things, Well, that's true,
缩放的事情,这是真的,
That's why it won't zoom, but it won't even pan,
这就是为什么它不会放大,但它甚至不会锅,
Why won't it even pan around, let alone zoom?
为什么它甚至锅,不让单独放大吗?
>> Content size,
> >内容大小,
>> Content size, exactly,
We haven't set the content size,
我们还没有设置内容大小,
So, this scroll view actually is panning around the content
所以,这实际上滚动视图浏览内容
size, it's just that the content size is zero-zero, So,
大小,只是内容大小是能见度为零的,所以,
when you are trying to pan around,
当你试图锅,
it's like you're not even over that zero, zero spot, and
就像你甚至不超过0,0点,
it's impossible to be over it, So, we want the content size
它是不可能的,所以,我们想要的内容的大小
to be encompassing this whole image here so
这里包括整个图像
we can pan around with it, so let's do that,
我们可以浏览,让我们来做,
Now, where do we want to set our content size?
现在,我们想要设置内容大小在哪里?
There's actually two times that we wanna do it,
有两次,我们要做的,
For sure when our scroll view is first hooked up here,
肯定当我们的滚动视图是第一次挂在这里,
we're gonna wanna set our content size,
我们要想设置我们的内容大小,
So I'm gonna say the contentSize here equals and
所以我想说这里的contentSize =,
what is our contentSize gonna be equal too? Well,
我们contentSize会平等吗?
it's our image view's frame size, okay?
我们的图像视图的外框尺寸,好吗?
We want to enclose our entire image view,
我们想要附上我们整个图像视图,
So, whatever the size of our imageView is,
所以,不管我们imageView的大小是多少,
that's what we the content size of our scrollView to be,
这就是我们的内容大小滚动视图,
But there's another time we're gonna wanna sent the content
但还有另一个时间我们要发送的内容
size, which is if our image changes, right?
大小,如果我们的形象改变了,对吧?
If you put a new image in there, then we're gonna have
如果你把一个新形象,那么我们会有
to adjust our content size to make a change,
调整我们的内容大小做出改变,
And luckily, woo hoo, we have this nice var down here,
呜呼,幸运的是我们有一个漂亮的var下面,
so that every time we set our image, we can do things,
所以每次我们的形象,我们能做的事情,
And sure enough, right here, I'm just gonna say,
果然,在这里,我只是想说,
scrollView,contentsize equals the imageView,frame,size,
滚动视图,contentsize = imageView,框架,大小,
Now, this might seem good, But actually this is very bad,
现在,这似乎不错,但实际上这是非常糟糕的,
And the reason for that is that, If we're in image
原因是,如果我们在形象
view controller, and we're getting prepared,
视图控制器,我们要做好准备,
Someone's going to set our image url,
某人要设置图像url,
That's how they're gonna prepare us right? So
这就是他们会让我们对吧?
let's follow what that's gonna do, So imageURL is going to
让我们跟随这是要做什么,所以imageURL
set the image to nil, down here, Set this image,
将图片设置为零,下面,设置这个形象,
to nil, and it's gonna try to execute this line of code,
为零,它会尝试执行这行代码,
and that is gonna crash, Because when we're preparing,
这将会崩溃,因为当我们准备,
our outlets are not set so this is nil, So the way around
我们店没有设置这是零,所以
that? Question mark, This optional chain, If it's nil,
了吗?
I won't be setting the contentSize of the scrollView,
我不会设置contentSize滚动视图,
but that's okay cuz later, I'll come along and
但是没关系因为以后,我会过来
do it here when the outlet does get hooked up, So,
做在这里当出口连接,所以,
this is just to remind you that any time you're accessing
这仅仅是提醒你,你任何时间访问
outlets and methods that might be called during prepare, you
渠道和方法,可以称为准备期间,你
need to optionally chain them, okay? So it doesn't crash
需要选择链?
your app during prepare, All right, so let's go ahead and
应用程序准备期间,好吧,让我们继续
see if that fixed everything, set our content size here,
看固定的一切,我们的内容大小,
Should be good to go, All right,
应该好了,好了,
here's our image, and look at that, scrolls nicely, rotate,
这是我们的图片,看那卷轴,旋转,
okay, scroll, Okay, and notice it has a kinda this little
滚动,好,注意到它有一个有点小
thing where you scroll too far and it bounces back,
事,你滚动反弹,太远
You can control that, by the way, and scrollView's one of
你可以控制,顺便说一下,和滚动视图的之一
its settings, all right? Oops, wrong rotation there, okay,
它的设置,对吧?
we got it? Now, of course, now we'd like to zoom in, We wanna
我们收到的吗?
look and see if we can find any of ourselves down here,
看看我们可以找到任何我们自己,
Maybe that's one of us right there, We're gonna zoom in and
也许这就是一个人,我们会放大和
see, But for zooming, as he was saying up above,
看到,但是对于缩放,正如上面他说的,
we need to make sure we set the minimum and maximum
我们需要确保我们设置最小和最大
zoom scale, Cuz actually the minimum and maximum
缩放尺度,因为实际的最小和最大值
zoom scale are set right now, they're set to 1,0, So
现在缩放尺度设置,设置为1,0,所以
that's minimum and max, it means no scrolling, All right,
最小和最大,它意味着没有滚动,好吧,
so let's set that, A good place to set that is probably
让我们集合,可能一套的好地方
when our scroll view is first hooked up as an outlet,
当我们的滚动视图是第一次连接作为一个出口,
So we'll just do this here, we'll say,
所以我们就做这个,我们会说,
scrollView,minimumZoomScale, Let's go really small,
minimumZoomScale滚动视图,我们去很小,
how bout 0,03, okay, 3% of the size will go,
怎么样0,03年,3%的大小,
make allow our image to be really small,
让我们的图像很小,
And maximum, just to show you the difference, we'll make it
和最大,只是向你展示不同,我们会赶到
only, so we can only be twice as big, Or, or we can even
,所以我们只能两倍大,或者,我们甚至可以
make it so it can't be bigger, right? 1,0 would be,
让它不能更大,对吧?
it can never be any bigger than it is,
它永远是任何更大的比,
It could be smaller, but not bigger, Which we might want,
可能是较小的,但并不大,我们可能希望,
because if it's allowed to be bigger than its natural size,
因为如果它允许比自然大小,
it's gonna start getting pixellated and
它会开始和上马赛克
we don't want that, But just so you can see it happening,
我们不希望这样,但是你可以看到它发生,
And what's the other thing we need to make zooming work? No
的另一件事我们需要放大的工作吗?
one remember? We need delegation, Yes,
一个还记得吗?
the scroll view needs to know which of its subviews
滚动视图需要知道它的子视图
you want to have the transform change, And
你想要转换变化,
it does that by asking you to delegate, So now we're gonna
它通过询问你委托,所以现在我们要
get to see delegates in action right here,
可以看到代表在行动,
So to make a delegate work, you need to set the delegates
所以委托工作,你需要设置代表
to be yourself, So I need to say,
是你自己,所以我需要说,
scrollView,delegate = self, Now, this is not legal,
滚动视图,委托=自我,现在,这是不合法的,
and this is going to generate an error, And hopefully you
这将生成一个错误,希望你
can kinda see why, we'll look at the error, and it says,
可以看到为什么,我们将看一下错误,和它说,
you cannot assign the value of type ImageViewController,
你不能指定类型ImageViewController的价值,
which is what self is, to the type UIScrollViewDelegate
这就是自我,UIScrollViewDelegate类型
optional, So I told you that the ScrollViewDelegate is
可选的,所以我告诉你ScrollViewDelegate
an optional UIScrollViewDelegate protocol,
一个可选的UIScrollViewDelegate协议,
and that's what it is, And of course,
它是什么,当然,
self isn't that even though it doesn't employ any methods and
自我不是,即使它不使用任何方法和
that protocol has only optional methods,
那个协议才可选的方法,
Because it needs to go up here and say yes,
因为它需要在这里说是,
I'm a UIScrollViewDelegate, Okay, so this is this class,
我是UIScrollViewDelegate,好吧,这是这门课,
UIViewController, saying I conform to this protocol, and
ui,说我符合该协议
as soon as I do that,
当我这样做,
the error goes away, and there's no errors, Even
错误消失,甚至没有错误,
though I didn't do anything, I didn't actually implement
虽然我什么都没做,但我实际上并没有实现
the UIScrollView delegate protocol, that's because all
UIScrollView委托协议,这是因为所有
the methods in UIScrollView delegate are optional, So
UIScrollView委托的方法是可选的,所以
I don't implement any, but they're all optional,
我不实现任何,但它们都是可选的,
So I've conformed to the protocol, But of course,
所以我符合协议,当然,
that's not gonna help us with our zooming because we in
那不是要与我们的缩放,因为我们在帮助我们
fact do need to implement a method, Now I'm gonna show
事实需要实现的方法,现在我要表演
you a cool way to do this with extensions, I'm going to add
你一个很酷的方法扩展,我要添加
protocol conformance to my ImageViewController with
我的ImageViewController协议一致性
an extension, And I'm gonna do that like this,
一个扩展,我要做的,
So I'm gonna make it so that it does not conform, okay,
所以我要让它不符合,好吧,
ImageViewController does not conform,
ImageViewController不符,
But I'm gonna add an extension down here, at the bottom of my
但是我要添加一个扩展,在我的底部
file, which is an extension to the ImageViewController,
ImageViewController文件,它是一个扩展,
which causes ImageViewController to conform
导致ImageViewController符合吗
to the UIScrollViewDelegate protocol, Okay, so by just
UIScrollViewDelegate协议,通过
putting this here, this error down here is gonna go away,
将在这里,下面这个错误会消失,
Because I've added an extension, which causes this,
因为我添加一个扩展,导致,
this class right here to conform to this protocol,
这类符合此协议,
Again, all the methods are optional so
再一次,所有的方法都是可选的
normally we would have to put a bunch of methods in here,
通常我们会把一堆的方法在这里,
But I am gonna put the one method we do want down here,
但是我要把我们想要的一个方法,
which is viewForZooming in scrollView,
这是viewForZooming滚动视图,
Now what's interesting, notice as I start to type this,
有趣的,注意当我开始这个类型,
it actually knows that I'm a UIScrollViewDelegate, so
其实知道我是个UIScrollViewDelegate,
it offers me that method as a choice, so
它提供了我这个方法作为一个选择,
I'll double click on it, Here's my viewForZooming in
我双击它,这是我viewForZooming
scrollView, I just need to return which view I wanna
滚动视图,我想我只需要返回视图
zoom in for us, Of course, it's that image view,
为我们放大,当然,那就是图像视图,
So I wanna just say return imageView, but
所以我想说返回imageView,但是
that doesn't work, Why do you think that doesn't work?
这并不工作,为什么你觉得不工作吗?
This imageView is private,
这个imageView是私人的,
Now, I could unmake it private, but
现在,我可以改变它的私人,但是
now everyone can see that image view, and
现在每个人都可以看到,图像视图
that's a little too unprivate, So there's another kind of
这是有点太unprivate,这是另一种
private called fileprivate, and what fileprivate means is,
私人称为fileprivate,fileprivate意味着什么,
it's private to everyone in this file, So
这是私人每个人都在这个文件中,所以
that allows this extension to see this image view, And
这个扩展可以看到这个图像视图,和
it's still private to everyone else,
它仍然是私人对其他所有人,
So everyone using my MVC who sees this, other files,
所以每个人使用我的MVC谁看到这个,其他文件,
it's still private, they don't see it, But this guy can use
还是私人的,他们看不到它,但这家伙可以使用
it, okay? So that's a different kind of private,
它,好吗?
fileprivate, All right, so we got the view for zooming,
fileprivate,所以我们的视图缩放,
This is, in fact, the view we wanna zoom,
这是,事实上,我们想要放大的视图,
So let's go ahead and take a look here,
让我们去看一看,
All right, here it is, We can still scroll around, and
好吧,在这里,我们仍然可以滚动
if we hold down the option key and get our two fingers here,
如果我们按下选择键,两个手指,
we can also zoom, Okay, and
我们也可以放大,好的,
we can zoom in really small, and we can zoom out,
我们可以放大很小,我们可以缩小,
But notice, it won't let me zoom any larger than
但是请注意,它不会让我放大任何大于
1,0 because I set that as my maximum zoom scale,
1 0因为我设置我的最大缩放尺度,
All right, so, the last thing I'm gonna do, well, I'll leave
好了,所以,我要做的最后一件事,好吧,我离开
this as is cuz I'm gonna post this code like this, and
这是因为我要发布此代码,和
you can play around with it, Next time, what I'm gonna
你可以尝试一下,下次,我要什么
do is add another MVC that lets us pick some NASA images,
做的是添加另一个MVC,让我们选择一些NASA的图像,
you can see any NASA images, And one thing we're gonna find
你可以看到任何NASA图像,有一件事我们要找到
about this images, they're huge, and even on our Stanford
关于这个图片,他们是巨大的,甚至在我们的斯坦福大学
network, they take a long time to download, And that's gonna
他们需要很长时间才能下载,网络会
be annoying, and so we are going to use multithreading
烦人的,所以我们要使用多线程
to keep our UI responsive,
保持界面的反应,
even though it's doing this very expensive thing,
虽然这样做很昂贵的东西,
which is downloading this huge file, all right? So,
下载这个巨大的文件,好吗?
I'll see you then, >> For
然后,再见> >
more, please visit us at stanford,edu,
edu更多,请访问我们的斯坦福大学,